- What's up everybody?
It's Enes here, welcome
to another episode.
This week, we're in Calabasas, California,
and about to tour this
incredible newly constructed
contemporary home right behind me.
We got incredible amenities
and some of the best views
we've ever seen on this channel.
We have a beautiful infinity
edge pool, basketball court,
amazing grounds, and
over 22,000 square feet
of interior square footage.
So we've got a lot to see today,
make sure to stick around.
Now stats on the house.
We got eight bedrooms, 14 baths,
22,000 square feet of interior space,
built on a 1.75 acre lot
and this property is
currently on the market
for $37,999,000.
As always, we will leave more information
about the property down
in the description,
and before we start our tour,
I wanna thank the listing
agent, Tomer Fridman,
for allowing us to tour
his amazing listing.
Now let's begin.
(upbeat music)
On the exterior we have this white walkway
taking us up to the front entry.
House is a French
contemporary architecture.
I love the smooth stucco
finish, steel casement windows
and all these copper
details like the gutters
and the flashings on the bottom.
Now let's go inside.
Alright, everyone,
here we are at the entry,
beautiful glass pivot door.
Now let's talk about this entry.
We have two-story ceilings here,
with skylights bring in natural light in
right above me we have these chandeliers
and we're gonna take this direction first.
And this is where we have
the formal living room
and formal dining room area.
Let's start with the formal dining room.
Table for ten, three chandelier's above.
We have built-ins on each side
and casement windows bringing
a lot of natural light in.
To this side of the home,
right in the center we have
this beautiful linear gas
fireplace clad with glass
and another seating area
right in front of it.
Ceiling wood panel ceilings are also here
and we have more additional seating areas
right in front of me.
Let's continue.
We have another feature wall on this side
with floating shelves,
and I love how they put LED lighting
right behind that as well.
And we're used to seeing
a lot of fireplaces
in formal living room areas,
this time we have a water
feature, which is really cool.
And this one actually has another amenity
I'll show that in a bit.
We have another picture
window on this side,
and of course we have the Fleetwood doors
pocketing into the walls,
opening up to the backyard,
and then the cool detail,
every single one of the
Fleetwood doors on this house,
they're all automatic.
Additional seating area right here.
And this whole space is complimented
with this bar set up on this side.
Now I love how they
clad the bar with marble
on top, on the side and up front as well.
We have all the amenities here.
We get one of these
mini push wine fridges,
there you go, dual elevation.
We have more cabinets on this side.
I love the built-ins up top
with these glass shelves
with inlet lighting, which is really cool.
It looks really exquisite.
I think let's give it
a shot, there you go.
We have the dishwasher here
and this is where we have
the sink for this bar
another detail,
Mikey, let's focus towards
that water feature.
There you go.
In case you wanna watch some TV.
- [Mikey] Yeah, that's really cool.
- It's pretty cool, right?
And there you go.
When you want that sleek look can go raise
there you have it.
- [Mikey] Just put it back up.
- That's right, now,
let's continue our tour.
We take this hallway.
We're kind of back at the entry
at the end of this hallway,
we have the front door right there.
Let's talk about this incredible steel
staircase design right here.
We have the steel frame, open riser.
We have LED lighting
underneath each thread,
glass railing all around the
staircase is magnificent,
it's right in the center of the home.
Right across, we have the
elevator access for this level.
Now, continuing this way,
we have the breakfast nook right here
with this beautiful marble
table chandelier above.
We have the Fleetwood doors
already pocketed in opening up
to the outdoor patio.
We'll talk more on that later.
And as we continue, we have
more built-ins on this side.
Everything is super sleek,
I love the hardware.
Let's get a close up, check this out.
- [Mikey] Oh wow!
- And you even have the plug set up right here.
Everything looks super sleek.
- [Mikey] How light is that?
- Super light, I love the hardware.
Now let's talk about the family room.
Again, family room has
an open corner design
on that side, Fleetwood doors
opening up to the backyard.
We have the gas fireplace
set up here with the TV.
I really like these
textured walls as well.
And we have a comfortable
seating area here.
Of course right on the other side,
we have another set of Fleetwood doors
pocketing into the walls,
opening up to another patio space.
Right across we have the guest house,
we'll talk more on that later
but now let's focus on
this incredible kitchen.
I love how simple and
elegant this kitchen is,
everything is nicely paneled
in, the contrast is beautiful,
we have a massive Island
upfront, pendant lights above.
Let's start with the Island.
We have the bar seating upfront.
Right in the center we have open shelving,
that contrasts beautifully.
Countertops continue.
We have the waterfall edge on this side.
Pop-up plugs here.
Mikey let's wrap around for a second.
So we have the sink right here,
fabricated out of the same countertops,
and let's get a close
up right in the center.
First of all, they have
this beautiful cover plate
for drain stone and then yeah,
you can see all those cuts,
how they kind of created that slope.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's really cool.
- Of course, let's start with this one.
There you go dishwasher number one,
we have another one on the other side.
I love how they're beautifully
paneled in looks seamless.
Also Mikey, can we get a
closeup on these cabinets?
They have the stainless steel
kind of edge reveal detail
that looks gorgeous in my opinion.
I love that detail.
- [Mikey] Yeah I feel like that kind of
is carried out through
a lot of areas of the house, yeah?
- Exactly, correct.
We have this panel refrigerate here.
It's a push of course, there you go.
This is the first one.
We have more built-ins right here.
Induction cooktop.
We have the vent above tuck nicely to the ceiling.
You get a little griddle.
Mikey let's get another closeup.
We get the cabinetry.
- [Mikey] Oh wow!
- [Enes] It's amazing isn't it?
- [Mikey] Yeah, that's a
fantastically well organized.
- Yeah, the hardware, all
these amenities, there you go.
I mean, it's incredible,
this is for sure the best
kitchen we've ever toured.
- [Mikey] I gotta show
that vent real quick,
I missed it when you
talked about it earlier.
- There you go.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- And we have more open shelving detail.
It kinda breaks the flatness
of this cabinetry design.
Built-ins on this side.
You're ready?
- [Mikey] Oh wow!
(Enes chuckles)
- Isn't this pretty cool?
- [Mikey] Yeah, I think we
should make some lemonade.
- No this is Fridge staging.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- I love it.
Overall, by the way,
these are glass panels.
Overall it's a very simple sleek design.
Of course we have another
set of pop-up plugs
on the other side.
Beautiful kitchen.
Kitchen is complimented with
this wine wall right here.
Of course it's temperature controlled.
Let's follow this whole
way continue our tour.
And there's the cool
little detail right there.
Coolest clock ever.
- [Mikey] Yeah we've been talking
about this almost all day.
This is like maybe my
favorite clock I've ever seen.
- I know.
- [Mikey] That's really cool.
- It is pretty cool.
Now I guess part of the kitchen
kind of continues on this side.
The other side of the wine wall.
We have another wine display here,
again, temperature controlled
and we have a small fridge on this side.
Let's get a close up some cabinetry here,
espresso maker, look at the backsplash
or like the back wall,
the glass with LED lighting
looks so cool, right?
- [Mikey] Yeah, that's really cool.
- And check this up.
This might be my favorite
detail in this house.
Look at these doors, coolest ever.
- [Mikey] Oh wow!
- Just like that.
- [Mikey] Yeah I think it'll probably
show better if you open it.
Let's do that one more time.
- Look how it falls then
seamlessly tucks into the wall.
- [Mikey] That's a really really nice.
- I mean it's gorgeous.
And we have another ice maker here,
small sink and actually
kitchen kind of continues
because right across
we have the catering kitchen come on in.
We beautiful upper cabinetry
sheet with glass panels
and all the base cabinetry,
all the built-ins are
beautifully paneled in
with stainless steel
finishes looks incredible.
- [Mikey] Yeah, and this is
my favorite room in the house.
There's something about
black and stainless together
that I just love, but it looks really like
the essence of minimalism in here.
- I hear you,
I'm pretty sure this is by
far the best caterers kitchen
we've ever toured on the channel.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- For sure without a doubt.
So let's start here.
We have the stainless steel
countertops, I love this detail.
Mikey, let's get a close up.
They welded and fabricated
a sink in the continued
to countertop into a sink.
- [Mikey] So they weld that and then they blast that smooth, right?
and then they blast that smooth, right?
- Yep, isn't that cool?
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Of course two dishwashers.
Nothing is compromised even though it's caters kitchen.
And as we continue, we have
the Meile gas stove here.
Commercial vent above cabinetry continues.
- [Mikey] Ah Nice warming drawer.
- That's right.
And on the other side we
have a built-in desk set up.
Mikey I got a question for you.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Why do you think we
have a desk over here?
- [Mikey] I can't imagine
it's easy to stay organized
when you're a chef cooking
for 10 or 12 people over
here in this little kitchen.
So a little desk to stay organized.
- Well you are correct.
I actually got a chance to talk
to the designer of this property
and mentioned to me that
he specifically wanted
to put this for the chef to
order the ingredients they need,
which is really cool, nice work area.
Now everything is beautifully paneled in
with stainless steel.
We have the freezer set up on this side
and other one right here.
Built-ins and right here,
this is where we have the
fridge setup, there you go.
Let's get a close up.
- [Mikey] Fiji for days.
- I mean overall, what an
incredible caterers kitchen.
Now let's go back to the hallway.
We have the staircase going up
to the second floor and then
the closeup look at the
risers they placed in glass.
- [Mikey] Oh, nice, mirrored risers.
I don't know if we've ever seen it before.
- No, we never did.
It's a cool touch and I love
the LED lighting as well.
Right behind me, we have
this store opening up
to a bedroom on this level.
King-size bed, beautiful back panel walls.
I love the light fixtures
from the ceiling.
And right here, we have this
massive gas fireplace assembly
with a TV cloud beautifully
with this marble door opens up
to a walk-in closet and the bathroom,
wherever we have a floating
vanity textured walls
and a beautiful walking shower.
Now let's go back to the
hallway and continue our tour.
- [Mikey] While we're walking,
I just gotta say y'all on the other side
of the camera wont see
this or experience this,
but each of these rooms smells
absolutely incredible, yeah.
- Incredible...
- [Mikey] I don't kow what they use
but every room smells different.
- You get a little bit
of a hint right here.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it smells incredible.
- Yeah, the whole house smells incredible.
Now we're in the powder room.
We have a floating vanity
design glass countertops,
travertine walls around us.
And on that side we had the toilet.
As we go back to the hallway,
we're back at kind of like the entry area.
This is where we have the staircase
and we take this hallway.
We have two more rooms to see.
Wrapping around right on the other side
of that powder room,
we have an additional powder room.
We have more darker tones here.
Again, walls are clad with
stone floating vanity design.
Mikey, I don't know if you
can see it on the camera.
You see the color difference
between the countertop
and the sink itself?
- [Mikey] Yeah, I don't
know if you realize this,
but this is a mirror of the other bathroom
except it's black.
- Correct and it's on the other side.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- And right here, let's show it.
This is where we have the toilet set up
with LED lighting on the walls.
- [Mikey] Just like the other side.
- Just like the other side, correct.
Now let's go back to
the hallway, last room.
Two pocket doors,
we have one on here,
one on the other side sealing
off the office, come on in.
We have two desks setups.
Beautiful built-ins on each side.
I guess let's show this side.
We have another one of these
sliding panels, there you go.
I love that you have the plugs as well.
This one is a front facing room.
We have the floating shelf design on the center and I know Mikey you're gonna think that I'm a nerd, but can we get a close up on the floors?
We have three floor plugs on this side,
two on the other side it's a nice detail.
So I wanted to mention
that overall great office
and that wraps our tour for this floor.
Now let's go back to the staircase
and check out the basement.
(upbeat music)
Alright, now let's talk
about this basement.
Let's start right here.
We have this hallway
and the door at the end
opens up to the 10 car
garage with epoxy floors.
We have a hallway storage right here
and this door, let's go inside.
This is where we have the laundry room.
Two washers, two dryers,
plenty of storage.
Now let's go back to the hallway
and we have another hallway
right here, two hallway closets
and the door at the end again
opens up to the 10 car garage.
Now let's go this way.
By the way this is where we
have the elevator access off
of the staircase.
And right here, we have this opening.
Let's actually briefly
go outside for a second.
We have this exterior hallway here,
which brings in a lot of natural light,
but at the same time, at the end,
you have the staircase
going up to your backyard,
which makes accessing to
the basement level easy,
and also on this side,
we have this texture stone
walls and on the bottom,
let's get a close-up.
We have the copper flashing.
- [Mikey] Yeah, and that's all
around the exterior, right?
- All around exactly gutters, everything.
Now, Fleetwood doors.
And we have another hallway
here, let's check it out.
I really liked the wood
tones throughout the house.
They clad all the walls here with wood.
And we have a electric
massage chair dry sauna.
Let's get a little tour.
We have the floating vanity
here, water closet on this side.
Mikey, let's pan up to
the ceiling for a second.
Are you seeing that rain head?
- [Mikey] Yeah, that looks,
it looks pretty unique.
- It's incredible, isn't it?
- [Mikey] There's like a design
to like the water spigots too.
I've never seen that.
- Yeah, there's for sure,
and this is your spa bathroom,
you have the marble walls,
Chrome fixtures, steam
shower, everything you need.
Now the other side, let's get a close up.
I know I didn't actually
need to go in there,
but this is where we have
the dry sauna there you go.
Fireplace, and you could
probably mount your TV here
if you need to.
- [Mikey] Yeah and I've never
actually seen a massage table
that's also a massager in itself you know.
- I think this is the first time
we are seeing something like
this, which is really cool.
We have the gym here nice and spacious.
We have the mirror wall on this side,
little bit of a bar area.
You get your fridge, your sink
set up, plenty of storage.
And at the end we actually
have set up Fleetwood doors
again pocketing into the wall,
opening up to the outdoor access,
that's where we have the staircase
going up to the backyard.
Now let's go back in.
We have more to see on
this basement level.
Now we're back at the landing
wood clad walls continue,
and this is where we have the wet bar,
I love the light tones
contrasting beautifully
with the black cabinetry.
Let's start with the Island.
We have the marble countertops.
It's book match with a waterfall edge.
We have the bar seating on this side.
Of course we have the
pop-up plugs right here.
Beautiful pendant lights above.
As we continue, we have
this beautiful back wall.
They use the same style of wood paneling
that we saw at the spa,
but they use that at a smaller scale
with the same color to give texture
to this bar setup right here.
Mikey, let's get a close
up on these bottoms.
I love how they clat even this
little section with Marble
which is really cool.
- [Mikey] Is that glass
on top of that as well?
- Exactly, these are glass shelves
but they have inlet LED lighting
inside, isn't that cool?
- [Mikey] Yeah, they look really unique.
- This bar is super sleek.
We have a wine fridge here
with one of these push doors,
there you go another fridge
on this side, nicely clad,
get a dishwasher.
I believe this is the
ice maker there you go.
We have the ice maker.
I love how they also recess
in this sink design right here
with a beautiful faucet. Overall
amazing bar, it's so sleek.
And we have a little bit of
a seating area right here,
personally, I love this
couch set up right here.
All right, let's continue.
Pocket doors, we have one right here,
we have another one on this side,
opening up to the movie theater,
come on in. Three tier seating.
We have the LED strip
lighting on the walls,
all they're nicely paneled.
And we have the screen on this side,
a bit of a more lounge and
kind of comfortable seating
on the lower level and right
above on the top two tiers,
we have these electric lounging
terrace made by Bugatti,
which is really cool,
and check this out the cup
holders you can heat and cool,
and there you go.
- [Mikey] Yeah, that looks
pretty comfortable there.
- It is pretty comfortable,
and this is this movie
theater is incredible.
It really is and I think it really matches
the rest of the house well.
So continuing our tour
right next to the bar,
we actually have a powder room.
Let's check it out real quick.
Floating glass vanity set up
with a textured back wall,
LED lit mirror, beautiful bathroom
- [Mikey] Yeah, and I love that contrast
between the white backlight
and the black wall.
- Agreed, agreed.
Moving on back to the hallway.
Now, as we continue this way,
we have the game room
right here and I must say,
this is probably the coolest
pool table we have ever seen.
We have a bit of a high
top seating over there,
chandelier's above TV on the side.
And right here, this door opens up to one of the bedrooms on this level, but egress access, walk-in closet, and a beautiful bathroom set up for the floating vanity and a walk-in shower.
Now this door opens up to the
second bedroom on this level
king-size bed situated on this side with a padded back wall.
We have a bit of a
seating area right here.
That's set up on this side,
set of windows bringing natural light in.
Right here, we have the full bathroom.
This one has a tub setup
with a textured walls
and they use the same
texture stone all the way
behind the floating
vanity design right here
and wrapping around.
This is where we have the
walk-in closet for this bedroom.
And that's pretty much it
for the basement levels.
Now let's take the stairs again,
go up to the second floor and
check out all the bedrooms.
(upbeat music)
Alright everyone,
here we are at the second floor,
we have two spacious guest suites
and the primary bedroom on this level.
Follow me.
We have this wide hallway skylights above
with panel ceilings continue.
I actually just realized a detail
Mikey, let's get a close
up on these skylights.
Are you seeing the LED strip lighting
all around the skylights?
I'm pretty sure they have
it at the whole house.
- [Mikey] Oh yeah, actually I
think I saw that at the entry.
What's that all about?
- I think they do that
so at night it still feels like a skylight
rather than just you know
have that dark glass.
- [Mikey] Yeah, well, I
mean, that looks really cool,
and I guess everyone will see
that here in a little bit.
- They're all gonna see
that in a bit, you're right.
All right, first of
all right here opens up
to the first guest
suite nice and spacious.
We have the skylight right in the center,
bringing natural light in.
Then this bedroom is front facing.
I love how cozy it feels.
We have the King size bed right here.
And the same ceiling reveal
detail is also in this bedroom.
This door opens up to the
walk-in closet, come on in.
We have the built-ins,
everything is nicely paneled.
We have the hangers,
drawers, everything you need.
Now let's go to the bathroom,
which is right here and
kind of the same finishes
that are also in this bathroom.
We have the textured stone back wall
floating vanity design.
I love these countertops and
how seamlessly, you know,
they transition into the sink
set up which is really cool.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's almost
hard to even see on camera.
It's that seamless.
- Yeah, I agree.
And we have the full walk-in shower here.
Same stone has also
brought it into the shower.
Let's go to the second bedroom,
which is right next to this bedroom,
and it's right here.
This one, I have a feeling
this one is staged kind
of like a kid's room.
We have a little bit of a makeup area,
little bit more of the feminine tones,
again, another front facing bedroom.
Nice and spacious.
We had the bed situated on this side
with these ceiling mount light
fixtures, built-in closet.
Pretty much the replica of the
other bedroom, same finishes,
hangers, drawers, everything you need.
- [Mikey] Yeah and I got to say
just like every other bedroom
in this house...
- I know what you're going to say.
- [Mikey] This one smells really good.
- Really good right, I agree.
And this is where we
have the shower set up,
walking shower, textures,
stone, back walls,
floating vanity, little bit of
a different countertops here
and a freestanding tub.
Let's go back to the hallway now.
And I want to briefly talk
about the staircase design.
Right at the end, this is the staircase
that we showed it to you
guys right after the kitchen.
And it comes up.
We have a massive picture window
bringing natural light in.
You see this railing design?
I thought it was really cool.
They kind of have this
like recess section.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's really cool.
- It looks really modern
and they topped it off with
this marble right here.
- [Mikey] Once again, I bet
it looks really cool at night.
- I bet, I bet, now let's go to
the most important bedroom in
this house, primary bedroom,
first off, look at this pivot door.
It's insane and we have
this massive handle.
Come on in guys, we have the
pocket doors already opened up.
This primary bedroom is one of the best
we've ever seen on this channel,
and I really mean that because
of the amenities, finishes,
scale, views, everything.
This is the full package, right?
We have the best situated on this side.
I love how they went with
the wood-paneled look
on the back wall here as well.
Ceiling mount light fixtures.
Bed is perfectly situated for
the view and the backyard.
And we have that incredible
infinity edge pool
in the backyard.
We're also gonna see that in a bit.
Now we have the linear gas fireplace here,
clad beautifully with stone.
Everything is book
matched, TV on this side,
again, pocket doors
opening up to the balcony
and we have new bathrooms.
First one starts right here,
let's go in. Natural stone walls.
And right here, we have the first closet.
Nice and spacious.
Again, we have everything
you need LED lighting,
hangers, drawers, you
know, all the good stuff.
And this is where we
have the first bathroom.
So I want to talk about
this walk-in shower.
Let's go inside for a second
because this one is incredible.
First off stone everywhere,
skylights above.
We have Chrome fixtures
throughout your handheld.
I'm assuming this might be steam,
I actually don't know
exactly but it's a steam
or another shower head.
We have the head above and check this out.
You've got this section right here
with all these body sprays.
I've never seen anything like this,
it's supercool
- [Mikey] Yeah, this is, this is crazy.
- This is next level.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- For sure.
Now we have another
Fleetwood door right here.
I mentioned it earlier
everything is automatic.
- [Mikey] We don't really
get to see that enough,
you know when I first moved to LA,
I was expecting like all these
houses we were gonna tour
were gonna be automatic doors.
- Not all of them have it.
You're right.
And there you go opens
up to your balcony setup.
We have another set of
floating vanity design,
fabricated countertops.
I have another detail
and I bet none of you
guys actually caught this.
I'm talking about my
videographers over here.
So we have a water closet here, right?
Mikey, go inside I'm gonna close the door.
- [Mikey] Okay, this is a first.
(both chuckling)
- And well, is that correct?
You miss it?
- [Mikey] This is for the financial guru,
you always got to check your ticker.
- That's right you always
got to check it right?
Let's close this door.
Let's go back to the bedroom.
Let's go towards the other
bathroom in the closet.
Actually, now that we
covered this section,
there's also this section, right?
Bit of a seating area, some
built-ins here, espresso maker.
We have the scene by folding door
also here, if you want to close this off,
which is really cool.
And we have a bit of a
desk set up on the side
and now going through this floor.
Now this is the real
closet check this out.
I mean, this looks like a exquisite store.
- [Mikey] It smells like one too.
- It smells like one too.
We have dual islands, drawers, shelving,
beautiful LED lighting.
These exquisite chandelier's
above, skylight,
I mean, we have everything you need.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's incredible.
- This house is a showstopper for sure.
Now another set of pocket doors right here
going into the second bathroom.
Well, I guess let's start here.
We have the water closet
with a privacy glass,
right on the other side.
Massive walk-in shower,
beautiful Chrome fixtures,
rain head, recess
lights, marble everywhere
with the bench design
even LED lighting is also brought in here.
Now let's go back to the
bathroom, TV on this side.
Beautiful freestanding tub,
look at that tub filler.
Again, we never seen you
you fixtures, everything,
every detail in this house is so gorgeous.
- [Mikey] Can we turn this thing on?
- Let's give it a shot.
(water flowing)
- [Mikey] Yeah, that is really cool.
- That is really cool right?
And we have this massive
picture window perfectly focused
towards the view.
And this is where we
have the vanity setup.
Fabricated countertops with
hidden drain sinks,wall fixtures
Your mirror set up. An amazing bathroom.
Now I want to take you guys through here.
We have another set of Fleetwood doors
pocketing into the walls,
opening up to the balcony
for the primary bedroom.
We have space heaters here,
a bit of a sitting area,
incredible views.
And by the way, you get
the incredible views
and the privacy straight from
your bed, which is amazing.
And we have more additional
outdoor space right here.
This section is not covered,
but we get a fire pit right in the center,
beautiful wood decking,
and actually we can see some
of the finishes of the house
from here, smooth stucco,
copper gutters and your slate roof.
Overall, this is an
incredible bedroom suite.
The closets, the
bathrooms, the scale, views
are unbelievable but I think
this balcony, the view,
the setting and this incredible
backyard really tops it off.
Now, why don't we go downstairs
and check out the grounds
and this incredible infinity edge pool.
(upbeat music)
Alright everyone, we are
back in the first floor.
This is where we have the kitchen.
Of course, Fleetwood with
doors pocketing into the walls
opening up the side of the patio.
We wanna start from this side
because this is one edge of the property,
and we're gonna work our way
to that incredible infinity edge pool.
Right in front of me
we have the guest house
before we do that right
next to the guest house,
we have a putting green, how cool is this?
- [Mikey] Yeah, we don't really
get to see this that often,
but it's a nice little amenity to have.
- I don't know if it's little Mikey
it's a pretty good size putting green.
- [Mikey] Typically the ones that we see
are about a third of the size maybe.
- I agree, I agree.
Now let's go toward our guest
house which is right here,
we already have the
pocket doors opened up,
it has a nice corner glass detail.
And this is where we have the fireplace,
a bit of a seating area.
And it's a full guest house.
I mean, it has a dining
area, very sleek kitchen,
you have paneled in fridge, induction,
plenty of uppers even have built-ins
not to mention Mikey,
I need you to get a close up right here.
Look how gorgeous this kitchen sink is.
Now let's go inside.
This is where we have the bedroom.
Again, very spacious.
You get a bit of a desk
set up on this side,
TV, king-size bed.
And right here, this door
opens up to the bathroom
and the walk-in closet.
Again, textured stone walls are also here
with a casement window on top
for ventilation floating vanity,
beautiful bathroom and closet.
Now let's go back out.
We've been walking for
a while in this house.
Lots to see, right?
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's
been a long walking day.
- I agree, now let's talk about
the house for a little bit.
We have the kitchen right here opening up
and patio kind of extends out.
This is where we have the family room.
I mentioned it earlier,
has a nice corner glass
design here as well.
And right here,
we get this covered section
outdoor TV, fire pit.
That's where we have the breakfast nook.
You get an outdoor dining
area, beautiful space.
And with these pocket doors,
we get this amazing flow.
- [Mikey] Yeah, and what about
that sound we're hearing?.
- Yeah, this is another
special feature of this home.
So we have this massive retaining wall,
and they turned it into
this amazing water feature
that brings a lot of tranquility, peace
and amazing sound to this backyard.
- [Mikey] Yeah, sounds
like there's a river
running back here.
- Mikey, just look at it.
Look at the flat grass
section we have right here.
We have the water feature,
we get the privacy,
we get amazing views from the pool area,
amazing this property.
- [Mikey] We haven't even
gotten to the pool yet.
- That's like the best part
of this home in my opinion.
Now, as we continue right here,
we have another set of Fleetwood doors.
That's why we had the entry.
And as we continue to walkway,
this is where we have the
formal living room area
and walkway takes us to
the side of the property.
This is the other end
where we have a half court,
basketball court.
- [Mikey] Yeah, this is something
else, this is different.
- Something else.
- [Mikey] This hits different with me.
- I know, I feel you.
I mean, we literally have
everything in this house.
Views, privacy, incredible
interior square footage.
By the way, we have a little
gate right there opening up
in case you need to park
some cars over here,
you can do that as well.
- [Mikey] Yeah, not a basketball fan,
park your cars here instead.
- You can do whatever you like, right?
We have the retaining
walls on the other side
landscaped beautifully,
giving a lot of privacy to this property.
And this is the staircase
access to the basement level.
Pretty cool.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Now let's take this
hallway now let's continue.
And we have a really cool
outdoor seating area at the end.
Let's check that out.
I can't wait to talk about
this pool by the way.
It's incredible.
Now we have this outdoor
seating area, fire pit,
right in the center.
They formed this out of concrete.
So you get that little bit
of that industrial look.
Same thing the bench design is
also formed out of concrete.
We have a beautiful seating area here,
complimented with an 85 inch outdoor TV.
And I mean, the views
from here are incredible,
but we're gonna get a closer
look from the pool area.
So let's go back.
Now, this pool, the size is incredible
also it's above ground
and you have an infinity edge all around.
We have the bar shelves right here,
spa in the center and
it is focused perfectly
towards the view.
Of course the pool
comes to the pool house.
First door, we get a full bathroom here.
Let's check it out.
- [Mikey] Nicest bathroom I've
ever seen in a pool house.
- I know right?
Floating vanity, beautiful marble walls,
marble walk-in shower.
Even here you get a rain head.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's great.
- It doesn't get much better right?
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Now, let's continue
touring the pool house.
We have the same wood clad also here.
Your pool house has an amazing bar.
I mean it's amazing clad
with marble, dual elevation.
You get a dishwasher sink.
On the other side, you have
your ice maker, small fridge,
you get your TV, recessed and
LED lighting space heaters.
You got every amenity possible,
not to mention you get
another covered seating area
on this side with a fire pit,
all focused perfectly towards the view.
You may think where's the
barbecue set up, follow me.
It is right here, right
behind the pool house.
We get the full gas, barbecue
sink, everything you need.
Now let's go walk to the edge
of the pool, it's incredible.
So this pool is quite ambitious,
both on size and how it's
been planned and designed.
But I tell you something
it's worth every penny,
because it compliments this house so well,
you know it kind of has a timeless look,
but yet it's very contemporary.
We have these incredible peaceful views.
I've never seen any view
like this before, ever.
It's so peaceful, we have
the Santa Monica mountains.
This is something to experience.
- [Mikey] Yeah and this is a neighborhood
we're kind of new to.
We spent a little time in Calabasas,
but I'd love to spend more time
out here, go for on a hike.
Looking down, there's
hiking trails all below us
and it's just really unique.
- I agree and something about this house,
like we taught a lot of
high price point homes
and we get the pricing,
and write the location, the finishes,
but this one, when you tour the home,
you look at the location,
the setting, the grounds,
and you look at this view, it makes sense.
The price point you get
it and you feel like
you're are buying a $40 million home.
Well, that's just for the tour,
it's been an incredible
day, touring this home,
sharing it with all of you.
But of course this tour
will not be complete
unless we spent few more hours,
so we can show this house
to you guys at dusk.
(upbeat music)
Alright guys, that's it for the tour.
Now, before we end this video,
I would like to summarize
my thoughts on this house
and briefly talk about the neighborhood.
This house is located in a gated community
called Oaks of Calabasas
which includes 500 homes.
Within that gated community,
there's a smaller gated community called
the estate of the Oaks
which only includes 54
properties out of that 500.
Of those 54 homes, only 16
of them sits on a Ridge line,
and this property is one of them.
The views from the Ridge
line are incredible,
you guys saw it earlier.
We have the Santa Monica
mountains, Malibu Canyon road.
It's definitely a very
peaceful and tranquil setting.
On top of that we have that
amazing infinity edge pool,
perfectly framing that view as well.
Now in terms of the house,
my favorite two rooms are the kitchen
and the primary bedroom.
I love the kitchen design,
it looks very sleek,
the contrast is beautiful.
We have the massive Island upfront
and you have all the functionality
you need in that kitchen.
Also right around the corner
we have the caterer's kitchen,
which is a great compliment
to the main kitchen.
And I love the contrast
between the stainless steel
and the black glass cabinetry.
Primary bedroom overall was amazing.
You had the spacious bedroom complimented
with the coffee bar, two
bathrooms, two closets,
amazing balcony and you
had the incredible views.
Lastly, I wanna give
credit to the designer
and the developer of this project.
It took them six years to build this home
and pulling off a project like this
with an infinity edge pool like that
and making the best out of the
grounds is not an easy task.
For that I wanna
congratulate the developer
and the designer Michael Palumbo
for doing an amazing job.
Finishes in this house are incredible.
Overall, they did a great job.
Lastly, I want to thank the
listing agent Tomer Fridman
for allowing us to tour
his amazing listing.
Thank you all so much for watching.
If you enjoyed this video,
make sure to give us a, like,
if you have any questions or input
as always leave us a comment down below,
if you haven't already make
sure to subscribe to our channel
and we'll see you guys next week.
(upbeat music)