- This is the biggest and
the most expensive home
currently on the market
in the United States,
with an asking price of $295 million.
It is also the most requested
episode on our channel,
so we're really excited for this tour.
Now, this home features
105,000 square feet
of interior space, 21
bedrooms, 49 bathrooms,
private nightclub, breathtaking views,
situated on this incredible promontory.
And let's get started.
(eerie bass tone)
(upbeat bass music)
- The One is a property
that has been legendary
to all Angelinos for the last 12 years,
and worldwide in the last decade,
has become this iconic sort of figure.
It's kind of bigger than
life, it's more than a home.
It's an entity.
And the reason why Angelinos
have followed this property
is because there are so many changes
that have taken place now in Los Angeles,
which don't allow you
to ever recreate this.
For one thing, there are nearly
30,000 cubic yards of dirt,
30,000 cubic yards of
dirt that were removed,
excavated to create this, okay.
And you are on four
acres, almost four acres,
up the longest driveway you've ever seen,
and landing on top of the hill.
One of the highest
elevations in all of Bel Air.
So for all of those reasons,
and then add the icing on the cake,
which is a 360 degree view.
You are in one of the most sought after
and iconic properties
in all of Los Angeles.
(relaxed music)
- We're gonna start our
tour on the motor court.
Long driveway brings you up here,
and halfway through the driveway,
you actually have an entrance point
to your subterranean garage.
And behind the property,
we also have an amazing
detached guest home
that we're gonna tour later in the video.
Now, coming here, we
have this paved floors,
palm trees, amazing scale.
And coming to this section,
we have the marble walkway
taking you to the front door.
I love the moat that they have off of the entry.
You have a art installation on your right,
two massive skylights
embedded into the pool,
allowing natural light
to the lower section.
And before we get in here,
I also want to thank the listing agents,
Rayni Williams, Branden
Williams, and Aaron Kirman
for allowing us to tour
this amazing listing.
And we will be actually talking
to Rayni and Brandon later in the tour.
Now, coming back here,
the front facade is also clad with marble.
I love the grid details
on the right hand side.
This overhead section
has built in LED lighting
to light up the entry, and coming here,
we have a fingerprint scanner,
and your marble door actually
recesses into the wall.
Now, coming here, this is where
we have the spacious foyer.
Oversized marble on the floors.
We have this art installation
right in the center, that rotates.
Beautiful chandelier above,
and throughout the property,
I'm gonna talk about the scale
because everything in this
house is so oversized.
So grand, and this is
just your entry here.
You have seating on
each side, suede walls,
and sliding glass doors
seamlessly takes you to the outdoors.
Now, coming back here to the entry,
we have this long hallway
taking us to two special rooms.
First, we're gonna check out the office.
Now, before we get there,
on our right hand side
we have one of the staircases
going up to the second floor.
And coming here, we have the office.
25 foot high ceilings,
skylight right in the center,
walls of glass facing the views.
We have water surrounding the entire room,
and this corner glass looks
towards your motor court.
Scale is amazing.
We have the desk set
up right in the center.
And the entire room is complimented
with Italian lacquer finished cabinetry,
with LED lighting, that
looks really sleek.
And on top of that, right above us,
we actually have the balcony
looking down on this room,
and we're gonna check that
space out later in the tour.
Now, bringing everybody back to the entry.
Again, we have the staircase on our left,
going up to the second floor.
This opening takes us to
a beautiful powder room
with a marble pedestal sink,
and marble finished
wall with a mere accent.
And coming here, we have the main lounge.
- This is the king's
lounge, where he entertains.
Walls of glass, explosive
views, two king palms.
You have this beautiful art wall,
with this 20 foot fireplace,
you have this beautiful lounge.
- I mean, this is amazing.
And Branden, furniture looks small here.
Room is so big, it's insane.
How many square foot
you said this room was?
- I think this is about 3000 square feet.
- That's incredible,
I mean, these are good sized
couches and sofa setup.
And it's insane, and you
have another one over there.
- This is the secondary lounge.
This is my favorite lounge because this is
where you have the most
explosive views in Los Angeles.
You have the grand piano, oversized,
and then you have the biggest
views in all of Los Angeles.
This is the king of the year.
And it has one of my favorite art pieces,
which is the Murano glass,
it's the angel wings.
And you know what that's for?
Because this view is why they
call it the city of angels.
(dance music)
- Now, I'm gonna take
an interesting route.
I'm gonna bring everybody here.
We have the elevator
access, back to the foyer.
Of course, it opens up to the outdoors.
We're gonna check out
the backyard in a bit.
And coming here, we have
the formal dining room area,
gorgeous table right in the center,
that currently sits 16 people,
but I'm sure you can add few
more chairs on each side.
Chandeliers above, and
again, just the scale,
25 foot high ceilings.
Everything about this house is so grand.
Now, I wanna take everybody this way.
This entire glass panel actually goes
into your walk-in wine cellar
that is temperature controlled.
And these are for your big bottles.
And you have seating areas
within your wines cellar.
This is mind boggling.
We have never seen
anything quite like this.
Now, I wanna bring everybody back
to the formal dining room area.
This is the main hallway that
takes you from the front door.
And coming here, we
have an amazing opening,
with this art installation
that starts from the second floor ceiling,
goes down all the way to the lower level,
complemented with a water feature.
This is a polished chrome piece.
And I'm sure just the installation
of this sculpture took over a year.
Now, come in here.
We have another staircase
going up to the second floor.
And this is where we have the art gallery,
just an open space, on
our right hand side,
we have the moat off of the entry.
You have your lighting
perfectly positioned.
And at the end of this hallway,
we have a guest bedroom.
So let's go quickly check that out.
Seating area off of the
entry, king size bed,
with a patted back wall, super spacious room.
Has a door that opens up to
the motor cor for easy access
And come in here,
I'm trying to figure out
which details I wanna point
because there are so many.
Let's quickly check out the
bathroom, it starts here.
Marble floors, marble walk in shower
with this mosaic detailed chrome finishes.
Toto toilet that opens up as
you walk into the bathroom,
floating vanity, walk in
closet, everything you need.
Now, let's go back to the hallway.
And at the end of this hallway,
we have few powder rooms to serve
the first floor of this home.
It starts right here,
we have a gorgeous marble
pedestal sink, chrome fixtures,
another Toto toilet, everything you need.
Now, coming back to the hallway,
we're gonna go this way.
We'll be walking a lot in this home.
I mean, Mikey, look at the
scale here, I just keep walking.
- [Mikey] Yeah, I haven't gotten
the chance to talk much yet
because I'm a little bit overwhelmed.
We've done a lot of walking already,
but we've really just
started, so let's keep going.
- Absolutely, double doors
open up to your library.
Now, I say library,
but this room actually
has built in ventilation
for a cigar lounge, that way
you can actually smoke here
and you won't even smell.
In fact, Mikey, let's get a close up here.
You can see all these
built-ins with chrome details.
I love the veneer of the wood cabinetry
and the gloss finish.
You have the seating
area right in the center.
Vintage "Playboy" covers on this side,
which is a unique detail.
And I personally love those wall sconces
that are brass finished and oversized.
- [Mikey] And if there's a bunch
of vintage "Playboy" covers
on the wall, and you're talking
about brass wall fixtures.
- I'm just trying to keep
it straight line here.
We got a lot to cover on this house,
so I'm just trying to keep it quick.
It's a cool touch, open
shelving, TV, more storage,
and humidors, and everything you need.
All right, let's go back to the hallway
and continue our tour.
By the way, Mikey, can
you expose to the outside?
Look at the views here.
We have Downtown Los Angeles
from every angle of this home.
This is just amazing.
Of course, you have
sliding glass doors here,
opening up to the
outdoors and coming here.
This is where we have the
family room and the kitchen.
I'm gonna start our tour on the kitchen.
It is super sleek, I love
this polished cabinetry.
Waterfall edge on the island.
This is for sure one
of the biggest islands
we have ever seen on this
channel, nicely decorated.
Glass panels, I mean, look
how sleek these details are.
I'm pretty sure this
is a rose gold finish,
which is something we
don't see quite often.
And of course, you have
your Miele built ins,
two induction cooktops with a popup vent.
Builtin espresso maker, sorry, Mikey,
I'm pushing your left and
right, but these are cool.
I wanna have one of these.
- [Mikey] We've seen one of those before.
- We have tried one of these before.
- Yeah, actually in another one
of Rayni and Branden's listings.
- That is correct, all right.
We have two Miele induction
cooktops here, with popup vents.
Right next to that, we
have the first prep sink,
second one on this side, pop up plugs.
Very modern, very sleek kitchen.
Now, let's go back into the family room
so we can check out the
seating section over there.
Two L-shaped couches,
gorgeous coffee table right in the center.
I love the chandelier
ceiling lighting over here,
that really ties the space.
Of course, you have your
recessed in TV to the wall.
Linear gas fire place,
suede walls, cozy room.
Marble clad wall on that side,
and sliding glass doors
opening up to the outdoors.
Mikey, let's go check it out.
And I also wanna mention,
they're still putting some
of the finishing touches
in this estate, they're
still working certain areas.
We cannot tour it all,
but we're gonna try to do our best
to show you guys everything, right.
We have another hallway here,
powder room for this part of the home.
and coming here, of course,
these massive sliding glass
doors open up to the outdoors.
As soon as you walk in,
Downtown Los Angeles is
right in front of you.
This is just incredible, the views here,
the scale of this property,
the scale of this backyard.
In fact, Mikey, let's take
everybody to the grass section.
I love these palm trees that are right
in the center of the backyard.
To give everybody a quick
scale, that's the foyer.
That's the main lounge
that we toured earlier.
We have the bedrooms on the second floor
and the lower level that
we're gonna see in a bit,
but more importantly, look at these views.
And they did a really clever touch here.
They have a 400 foot jogging trail
that's right below this moat.
That way they have the
glass railing there,
since this property's on a hillside,
which allows this moat
to have no glass railing.
And from any part of the first
floor or the second floor,
you'll look at your views undisrupted.
This is simply amazing.
I mean, you can literally see
the mountains all the way back.
Hollywood Hills, Downtown,
Century City is down below you,
Pacific Ocean, these are without a doubt,
one of the best views we have
ever seen on this channel.
Mikey, you look a little speechless.
- [Mikey] We're just so high up here too.
But I was actually looking behind me
at the ocean views over here,
which we'll see in a second.
- Absolutely, now, we're
coming to the side backyard.
Let's just call it that.
We have the jacuzzi
here, which is oversized.
Marble floors, even on the outdoor.
That's your covered
patio space right there,
with a massive built in TV.
And this is your main pool
that has three infinity edges,
marble clad, mosaic on the bottom.
And you get so much outdoor space.
I mean, property is pretty
big, let's just face it.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- And not only you get amazing
interior square footage,
you get a lot of outdoor square footage.
And I wanna particularly
cover this section
because you have so many
more amenities on this wing.
You have an outdoor dining area,
another covered seating,
with TV, small wet bar.
And right behind this section,
we have the outdoor kitchen.
This is without a doubt,
one of the best outdoor kitchen slash barbecue areas we have ever seen in any residential home.
You have so much cabinetry,
multiple fridges,
ice maker, teppanyaki, sink.
And focusing into the other side.
Of course, you have your outdoor grill,
warming drawers, vent above,
and you have more grills here,
literally everything you need.
And that wraps our tour on
the exterior and the backyard.
Now, I wanna take everybody back inside
so we can check out the lower level.
(upbeat music)
- This is the biggest home in the world,
at a 105,000 square feet of living space.
It is divided up by a structure
of 30,000 square feet,
that is actually the home, and
then under belly of the home,
which includes a nightclub, a four lane bowling alley,
a spa, a gym, and when I
say gym and when I say spa,
I mean, it's really so
much more than that,
and you're gonna get into those details.
But this encompasses anything and everything you could ever imagine in a home.
We decided to do something really exciting
and never been done before on
a property of this caliber.
So myself, Branden
Williams, and Aaron Kirman
are going to take this, along
with Concierge's Auction,
out to the world.
And we're going to allow
the bidding process
to be won over by the
person that really wants
to make this their home, their everything,
because this is so much more than a home.
(dance music)
- All right, everyone,
here we are on the lower floor landing.
Before we continue our tour here,
I wanna turn back and talk about
this floating marble staircase design.
I say floating because it's actually
not attached to the wall here.
And it's all clad with marble,
has the recessed wall
lighting, glass railing,
and you come to the
landing of the lower level.
First, we have this
art gallery space here,
and I wanna take everybody this side.
Like I mentioned earlier,
we're gonna walk a lot in this house.
This door actually opens up
to the subterranean 50 car garage.
They're still working on the house
and finishing some of the areas,
but I wanted to bring everybody here
because this is a great space.
Massive door opens up from the
driveway and brings you here.
We have all this lighting on the ceiling.
And they went with darker
tones for this space.
Now, coming back here,
marble floors throughout.
I wanna talk about the feature
wall that's in front of us.
With the butterfly
details and the portraits,
multiple seating areas,
and the space continues.
I mean, look at this hallway
here, this is incredible.
Now, we have a seating area on this side,
with beautiful laquer
cabinetry, recessed in TV.
And we have two guest
suites on this level.
First one starts right here,
spacious room, king size bed,
sliding glass doors open
up to a private balcony.
And of course, this room also
has a full size bathroom.
Now, coming back here to the landing,
right next to the seating area.
We have this hallway taking us
to the second guest suite on this level.
Same finishes, darker
carpet on the floors.
King size bed, sliding glass
doors open up to a balcony.
And of course, this one
also has a full bathroom.
Now, coming back to the landing,
we're gonna go this direction.
On my right hand side we have
the elevator access and
some utility access.
And coming here, we have
another lounge area.
The amount of seating areas in this house
is kind of mind boggling.
Another U-shaped couch,
a linear gas fireplace.
I like the wall textures
that they have on this side.
And right here,
we have this marble table right
in the center of this room.
And this will essentially
be your wine cellar,
storage areas, they're of
course, temperature controlled,
another great common area on this level.
- [Mikey] Yeah, and
it's kind of hard to see
from the camera, but these wine cellars,
they don't have anything
in them right now,
but they're really deep.
They're 10 feet deep behind each
of these glass panels.
- Easy.
- [Mikey] So I'm sure once you put
your storage racks in
there, it's gonna fit a lot.
- I'm sure, incredible, I'm outta words.
Another bar, darker tones
with lighter counter tops.
And they used the darker finishes
on the walls here as well.
Of course, you have your sink, fridge,
another seating area behind it,
another seating area on this side,
another lounge on this level,
and we're gonna continue our tour.
Mikey, what do you like so far?
- [Mikey] It's hard to
argue with that backyard,
and that pool area,
but I think what we're about to see
is probably one of the
coolest parts of the house.
- This is the brains of the house.
And they spent so much money,
and it takes so much space
that they wanted to make it
a feature wall kind of a section.
That's why they have
this enclosed glass here.
And there you go, if you
wanna power a house like this,
with all iPads and all that,
this is what you need to do.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Amazing.
- [Mikey] That's not what
I was talking about though.
- What are you were talking about?
- [Mikey] Well, what
we're about to see now
is my favorite part.
- Oh, okay.
Yes, of course, I hear you.
Another powder room on this level.
And look at this hallway,
I like these art pieces.
It's creative, we could've
came up with that idea.
- [Mikey] Well, the best
art is always simple.
- There you go, another powder
room, gorgeous cabinetry.
I'm sure we're gonna see many
more bathrooms, let's see.
These are locker closets,
and kind of like basically
full size bathrooms,
his and hers, for your gym.
And when I say gym,
I'm not talking about a couple
hundred square foot room,
I'm talking about an amazing space,
and look at the scale here.
I mean, walls of glass opening up.
Is a little dark right now,
but you have the sparkling
sit in front of you.
This space, I'm outta words.
You literally have every
thing you can think of.
I like these ceiling mount
TVs, darker carpet here.
And right on the other
side we have a juice bar.
I say juice bar, but this
is a commercial kitchen.
I mean, the amount of cabinetry.
All you're missing is a stove and event,
and you have a commercial kitchen.
I like the bar seating, you
have all your equipment here.
This is where you drink your fresh juice.
Do your yoga, work out, and
it continues on this side,
and you have a living wall here.
I mean, this is mind boggling.
- [Mikey] Yeah, so if
you live in this house,
do you make your own juice?
- It depends what type of person you are.
- [Mikey] Yeah, I guess you
probably have someone on staff
that could just make some good
juice anytime you want it.
- Most likely.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Most likely, all right,
ready, indoor pool.
- My favorite room in that
house is the wellness center
because I've seen a million of them.
I've seen so many cold
plunges, and jacuzzis,
and hot tubs, and steam
showers, and saunas,
but this has something different.
This has an indoor lap
pool, it's about 90 feet.
Salt water, triple osmosis.
And above it, it just has green walls,
and it feels sort of like you're outside,
and you're just exercising
and swimming in this space.
And then it also has all
of the things I just said,
that have become common to us.
Which is the cold plunge,
and the dry sauna,
and the wet steam, and
all of those things.
And I think that all the
gyms that I've ever seen,
all the wellness centers
that I've ever seen,
this really touches on that
title in a whole different way.
(siren musical tone)
- And of course, scale
needs to match the house.
It's massive, salt water,
love the simple plaster.
Lights changing, you have
a mirrored ceiling detail,
with cold lighting, multiple seating areas
and lounge areas, sliding glass doors.
This is probably the best indoor pool area
in the city, with these kind of views.
And again, amazing.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's crazy.
- Outta words, living wall,
built in bench seating,
and it continues, Mikey.
By the way, this is the
hallway that we just walked.
And of course,
you have these automatic
sliding glass doors here.
Now, you will have
another set on this side.
It connects to, I
believe, powder room here.
And coming to this section,
you have another seating
area with a cold plunge,
two massage rooms, amazing views.
This chandelier right in the center
is probably one of the
biggest we've ever seen.
And first, I wanna go this way.
This is a full sized salon.
Maybe full size doesn't do justice,
it's like a commercial salon.
You have pedicure chairs, you
have hair washing stations.
You have chairs for you to
sit down and get a haircut.
And they have this nice kind of rose gold
and burgundy wool panels here,
which is kind of a retro detail.
LED lighting throughout, in another space,
it's part of your spa.
Now, coming back here, your spa continues.
And over here we have the steam showers,
walk in showers, heated
benches, where you sit down.
And in fact, they have
water lines on this section,
so you basically get water poured on you.
Have a dry sun on the other side,
and they're all built
like commercial spas,
where you have massive showers
and steam showers that can
accommodate up to 20 people.
- [Mikey] I'm a little bit lost right now.
I'm sure audiences also,
but show us how we get back.
- All, right, so we're basically
doing a full circle, right.
I just realized there's a powder room here
with a gorgeous marble
sink, and another wet bar.
And coming here, from
an interesting angle,
we just came to the bowling alley.
So now we're doing kind of almost like
a full circle on the lower level.
We have a golf simulator here,
of course, why not, if
you have a bowling alley,
it just compliments it.
This bowling alley is not a
residential bowling alley.
This is as if it was in a
hotel, and am I outta words?
I feel like I'm actually
doing a bad job explaining
some of the details.
- [Mikey] Well, there's a lot.
- This is a lot to talk about.
- [Mikey] I don't blame you, this is wild.
- We have here--
- [Mikey] We've seen
bowling alleys before,
but usually it's one lane, maybe two.
- And some of, they're
a little bit shorter.
It's just everything about it.
- [Mikey] It's like a full
size four lane bowling alley.
- Just incredible, wall
panels with LED lighting.
You have the TVs above,
amazing, just amazing.
All right, let's continue.
We mentioned this multiple times.
They're still working on
the house, so in this case,
I think they're doing some
touch up to the paint,
but this is your tequila bar.
I love this back lit glass detail here.
They have it on the bar
display too, all open shelving.
Normally this would be your seating area.
And let's go back to the main hallway.
If I'm not lost here, let's see.
At the end of this
hallway, behind that wall,
we have the nightclub.
But first, I actually wanna
take everybody this way.
We have few powder rooms here,
and that's the main staircase
that we came down from.
And before we wrap up there,
I actually wanna take everybody this way.
There you go, I'm learning this house.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- So another hallway, this
hallway takes us to a candy room.
This is a colorful touch to this estate.
We have these candy stations running
all the way to the ceiling.
LED lighting, round cabinetry.
I gotta give credit to
the developers here.
This is a nice detail,
and it's located perfectly
right off the entry
of the movie theater,
and this movie theater is something else.
In fact, Mikey, I'm gonna go left.
Why don't you go to the right?
Meet me at the movie theater
so everybody can get a full
scale of this amazing space.
Here we are, this is the movie theater.
I mean, calling this a movie
theater doesn't do justice.
This is a commercial movie theater.
And it's so decked out, with
the carpet, plush walls.
Dolby Atmos surround sound.
These recliner chairs, that may
look like comfortable sofas,
but you have all the amenities there.
Individual lighting,
and the ceiling heights,
the size of the screen here.
We have seen a lot amazing movie theaters.
I mean, a lot throughout the world,
but this one takes the win for me
because I would love to sit down here,
look at this massive
screen, and watch a movie.
Let's see if I can get this thing to work.
- [Mikey] You're like, and
watch some Enes Yilmazer videos.
- That's right, I'm trying
to make this work, Mikey.
And it's not pulling,
it's not doing anything.
Oh, there you go, I
mean, isn't this amazing?
I'm outta words, again,
some of the common areas in this house
is unlike anything we've ever seen before.
And that wraps our tour on this level
or on this part of this home.
I actually wanna take everybody outside
so we can check out the night club.
(dance music)
- This is the charity event room.
What would you call this room?
- I would call it a nightclub,
but I mean, it's just perfect
for any kind of utilization.
Obviously it's super open.
You have the commercial setup
for your events, speakers.
Not to mention this
massive screen here, bar.
It's pretty crazy.
- And more views.
- More views.
- 5,000 Square foot rooms
separate from the house.
So if you wanna throw an
event or an after party,
you bring 'em down here.
- Has a private entrance.
- Huge dance floor, huge
outdoor fire pit club.
And this is basically where you just get your groove on.
- That's right, you have the DJ booth,
you have the VIP lounge.
- And one of my favorite things,
the fire pit right over the view.
And this is another pool,
so if you wanna swim in
between all the fire pits,
you're right here.
- Branden, we got pretty
lucky, look at the views.
This is incredible,
I mean, you have Downtown
Los Angeles perfectly framed
in front of you.
- Well, this is why we
have the perfect weather
in Los Angeles, you don't
even feel the weather.
It's the perfect time, and
what is this right now,
70 something agrees?
- Yeah.
- Views, and we're in the dead of winter.
- This is amazing, Branden,
I need you to go in there.
Show people the scale, I
mean, this is incredible.
I mean, the scale here, just
the fire pit in the center,
it's pretty mind boggling.
- And this is where you're
entertaining with your friends.
And then if you want to
take a dip in the pool,
and you got this incredible water feature,
and this is the subterranean
level, the lower level,
but views all around.
(dance music)
- Here we are on the second floor landing.
We have beautiful hardwood
floors throughout,
seating area on my left.
But first I wanna actually
take everybody this way.
So we talked about this detail
on the first floor in the office,
and this is the overlook area.
And from here, you can really
get a true scale of this room.
We have a massive sky light above us,
cabinetry goes all the
way up to the ceiling,
walls of glass, just amazing.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's crazy.
- This house is just unlike
anything else we have ever seen.
We're tired, we're out of
breath just walking through.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- Now, we're gonna try to do our best
to show you guys as much as possible
because that's what we are known for.
We have four bedroom suites on this level.
Let's check out the first one here.
Gorgeous finishes here,
with king size bed,
patted back wall, suede wall on this side,
breathtaking views, I love
that Juliet balcony detail.
Of course, you have
your full bathroom here,
with marble clad back
walls, floating vanity,
walk in shower, everything you need.
Now, this is one of the access points
to the rooftop deck that we're
gonna check out in a bit.
And that right there is a
powder room for the landing.
Now, coming here,
this hallway takes us
to few other bedrooms.
This is where we have the second one.
This one is facing more
towards the backyard.
Of course, has a full bathroom too.
And coming here,
these are the two best
bedrooms we have on this wing.
Let's quickly check out this one here.
Of course, comes with
the king size bed setup,
hardwood floors, walls of glass,
facing these incredible views.
I mean, it literally looks
like a movie over here.
- [Mikey] Yeah, again, it's
an incredibly clear day today,
but the ocean,
I don't think we've ever seen a view
of the ocean quite like this.
- Absolutely, unless you go to Malibu.
- [Mikey] Yeah, I guess we
are a little bit farther west
than we usually are in the Hills.
- Correct.
- [Mikey] But still, it's
a great view of the ocean.
- It's an amazing view, look
at the scale here, Mikey.
Let's quickly check out the bathroom.
I mean, if we were to tour
every single room in detail,
this would be a three hour walkthrough.
Another Toto toilet,
I love this finish that they
have on these marble walls,
chrome fixtures, handheld,
floating vanities,
with this recessed in sink
design, that just looks gorgeous.
All right, Mikey, one more
room to see on this wing
so we can show it to everyone.
Again, we're gonna try our best,
there are so many rooms to see.
All right, come in here.
We have the last bedroom on this wing.
This one is the biggest, has
the same hardwood floors,
king size bed.
I just love the furnishings here too,
very minimalist, very to the point.
And before we check out the bathroom,
I actually wanna bring everybody here.
Another massive recessed
back steel column,
that way you have your
sliding glass doors pocketing
into the wall, opening up to this balcony
where you can appreciate
these views little bit more.
You have the art installation right at the edge of the promentory.
right at the edge of the promentory.
And this is unlike anything
we've ever seen before.
This is just truly mind boggling.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's incredible.
- All right, Mikey, let's go back inside
so we can show everyone
bathroom the for this bedroom.
Starts here, marble
finishes, floating vanity,
with the same sink design.
Free standing tub here,
with a chrome tub filler.
Walk in shower, same darkened
stone is also used here.
Of course, you have a walk-in closet,
pretty much everything you need.
Now, let's take everybody back
to the landing on the second floor.
We have this minimalist seating area here,
with another TV, suede walls.
Nice welcoming seating area
for all these four bedrooms
that we just toured.
Now, coming back to this floating hallway,
we can actually take a look
at the skylights bringing natural light
to the first floor and the lower level,
perfectly positioned.
And over here, you can actually
look down on your foyer,
which is just incredible.
I mean, look at the
scale of this chandelier.
I think this is the biggest chandelier
we have ever seen on this channel.
- [Mikey] Yeah, it's wild.
- A lot of firsts on this tour, for sure.
Now, glass railing all throughout.
Looking down, we have
the formal dining room.
You can actually see the
scale of the chandeliers too.
And coming back here,
we can take a closer look
at the art installation
that we talked about on the
main level here, looks gorgeous.
And even this section
frames a perfect view
of the Getty and the Pacific Ocean.
Now, coming back here,
we have the hallway continue on this side.
If you guys remember,
off of the motor court,
this is the section where we
have those metal grid details.
Another art gallery here,
lighting is perfectly positioned.
You even have the seating area.
And at the end of this hallway,
we have another guest bedroom.
This room is facing the
backside of the property.
Another king size bed, walls of glass,
opening up to a private balcony,
where you have the canyon views.
You can actually look
down on your guest home
and the tennis court,
Pacific Ocean on this side.
The rooms, the size, the
lengths, I'm outta words.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- All right, here we
have the full bathroom.
Another floating vantage design,
finishes are nicely uniform.
And another electric toilet.
God knows how much they had to
spend just on toilets alone.
- [Mikey] How many bathrooms again?
- 49 bathrooms, so I'm
assuming at least 49 toilets.
Probably more.
- [Mikey] Okay, it's not a
bathroom without a toilet, right?
- Yeah, but they may have multiple,
like in the nightclub and other areas.
- Yeah, that's wild.
I'm sure each of those is
probably $1,500 at least.
- I would say five, six grand at least.
- [Mikey] I mean, yeah,
I'm from South Texas.
That's how much that toilet
costs there in a nice house.
- I feel you, I mean, this is incredible.
Walk in shower, walk in
closet, everything you need.
Now, I wanna take everybody
back to the hallway.
And this wing takes us to
the primary bedroom suite.
Before we go in, elevator
access on our left, suede walls,
and these double doors
open up to the seating area
for the primary bedroom suite.
Nice couch set up, another
linear gas fireplace.
TVs nicely recessed into the wall.
And this room comes with its own bar.
Now, what I like about this bar design
or the cabinetry particular,
is the fact that it curves the wall.
Which is always a very
sleek and timeless detail.
You have another built in espresso maker.
You have your microwave, sink,
fridges, everything you need.
I'm assuming if you live
in a house like this,
you probably have
someone here serving you.
- [Mikey] I know you
all haven't seen it yet,
but this primary bedroom
in size and scale,
would probably cost five to $10 million
anywhere else in Beverly Hills or Bel Air,
or something like that, right?
- It could easily be a
standalone home on its own,
it's mind boggling.
- [Mikey] Yeah.
- All right, we have the island here.
That's it for the seating area
for the primary bedroom suite.
Now, let's continue our
tour on this hallway.
I love the vertical lighting
that they have on the walls,
going all the way to the ceiling.
This opening here takes
us to the first bathroom.
Oversized stone application
is also brought here.
We have a nice prep area, your
steam shower on this side,
walk in shower here,
with a massive rain head.
And again, just stone clad all the way,
with chrome fixtures, just gorgeous.
You have your vanity design here,
with glass countertops, of
course, free standing tub,
perfectly positioned towards the views.
And you have a nice Juliete
balcony detail here.
If you wanna slide open this door
and have fresh air coming
into this bathroom.
Now, here we have the first closet,
and this closet is gorgeous.
It feels like we're walking
into a high end boutique store.
Every detail, the way they
line the cabinetry here,
the soft cloth,
how the tracks are
underneath the cabinetry.
The rose gold finish, glass
cabinet fronts, chandelier here.
I mean, the list goes on and on and on.
If I wanted to do an episode here,
I feel like I can easily do an episode
just on the cabinetry here alone.
- [Mikey] Yeah
- It's gorgeous, now, Mikey,
let's take everybody
back to the hallway again
so we can tour the second bathroom,
which has more of the darker tones.
This one has more of the lighter
and kind of neutral tones.
Now, bedroom starts here,
but first let's go through this door
to check out the second bathroom.
As soon as you walk in,
you see this massive Jetta
tub right in the center.
And behind me,
we have these glass doors
opening up to the water closet.
Walk in shower, with the rain head,
and we have this steam shower here.
Literally everything you can think of.
Sliding glass doors open
up to a private balcony
for the primary bedroom.
And over here, we have
this gorgeous cabinetry,
with marble clad doors,
fabricated sink, chrome fixtures.
Just gorgeous finishes throughout.
Now, come in here, we have
the second walk in closet.
Island in the center, more
of the darker tones here.
Again, laquer finish, LED
lighting, glass panels.
Very timeless, very elegant,
definitely very chic.
Now, let's go check out the bedroom setup.
Coming back here, we have the door,
and this is where we
have the bedroom itself.
Bed set up on the left,
perfectly positioned towards the views.
I mean, we have the city
sparkling right in front of us.
It's gorgeous out here.
Hardwood floors, king size
bed, nice padded back wall,
with chevron pattern.
And coming here, right
in front of your bed.
We have the seating area,
another recessed back column,
that way sliding glass
doors open up to corner.
And again, the ceiling heights, the scale,
the space is just almost unexplainable.
Now, over this side,
we have more built ins.
This could easily serve as your office
for your bedroom or another seating area.
And stepping outside,
we have this private balcony
floating above the first floor,
and this is where have your
private all glass pool.
This is incredible.
I mean, the amount of money
spent on this pool alone.
I don't even wanna think about it.
You have a cold plunge on the other side
with a water feature, beautiful,
beautiful primary bedroom suite.
Now, that wraps our tour on this level.
I wanna take everybody upstairs
so we can check out the rooftop deck.
(dance music)
Now, we're on the rooftop deck,
and the first area I wanna take everyone
is the putting green.
For sure this is the coolest
putting green in the city.
I mean, look at these views.
Granted, it's been a long day.
We're running little late,
so as we are touring,
it's literally almost night right now.
But we're still showing it to you guys.
- [Mikey] There was a lot
of house to shoot guys,
so give us a break.
We had to start Enes's part a little later
than we usually do.
- Exactly,
but again, you guys are
getting the full experience.
Amazing putting green,
city is lighting up.
Also, before we leave this section,
I wanna mention behind the property,
we have a gorgeous detached guest home
with three bedrooms, four bathrooms,
amazing living room area.
Walls of glass facing breathtaking views
of the Pacific Ocean, has a
really nice infinity edge pool.
Unfortunately, since we are
running a little bit late here,
we're not gonna get a
chance to go down there,
but I'm sure our team got
some amazing shots of it.
So I wanted to mention that.
Now, continuing here, we
have the sky deck continue,
Epay decking on the floors,
multiple bar areas and
outdoor dining areas.
You have your fire pit here,
and like we mentioned earlier,
they're still putting some of
the finishing touches on this estate.
Now, coming to this section,
more outdoor seating areas
and the views are just
phenomenal, scale is incredible.
Lounging chairs, outdoor seating areas,
these gazebos, and again, the views.
Can we take everybody
all the way to the edge.
Getty and Pacific Ocean on the right.
Downtown Los Angeles on the left
Century City, Wiltshire
Corridor right in front of us.
This is without a doubt,
one of the best properties and best views
we have ever seen on this channel.
(dance music)
All right, everyone,
that's it for The One.
This was the most requested
home tour on our channel.
And I hope you all enjoyed this video.
I want to congratulate
everyone that was involved
with the build of this project.
And I also wanna thank the listing agents,
Rayni Williams, Branden Williams,
and Aaron Kirman for allowing us
to tour their amazing listing,
and share it with all of you.
And as always,
you can find more information
about the property
in the description of this video.
Lastly, if you enjoyed the tour,
make sure you give us a like,
subscribe to our channel,
and we'll see you guys next week.
(relaxed music)