- When I tug the end of this
thread, a short distance,
the spool zips towards me,
and because it's on a slight incline.
When I let go, it rolls away again.
So just with the slightest movement,
I can cause the spool
to zip back and forth.
How weird is that?
I stumbled upon this after
watching a six year old
Physics Girl video, link in
the description for that.
In the video, Diana poses the question,
what will happen when I pull on this cord?
Will the spool roll away
from me or towards me?
Actually, I think the question
with the more counterintuitive answer is
will the cord get longer or shorter?
Because you know, if you tog on a cord that's wrapped around a spool, you expect the cord to unspool a bit so that you have more cord.
But based on the shot that I showed you
at the very beginning, you
may already have figured
out that the spool will roll
towards you and the cord will get shorter.
The reason I started playing
around with it for myself is
because I wanted to answer
two follow on questions.
The first one, what happens in the limit
like you've got this distance
here, which is a measure
of how much room there
is left in the spool.
What happens as that
distance approaches zero?
As the spool gets full?
As a teaser, you end up with
infinite mechanical advantage.
And secondly, I wanted to
know what happens if you go
beyond that point, if you go
past the spool being full,
if the loose end of the
cord is below the ground.
But before we get into that,
let's see if we can explain
the counterintuitive answer
to the original question.
So when you pull on the rope
it gets shorter as the
spool rolls towards you
and there are actually two ways
of looking at why that happens.
The first way which is less
intuitive I would argue
is just to think about forces.
So forgetting all the detail,
you've got some object
it has a pivot point here
and you are pulling it
with a force from here.
So of course the object is going to move
around that pivot point in the
same direction as the force.
But then of course the pivot point moves
and so you have a rolling motion.
The other way to think about it
which is a bit more intuitive for me
is to think about what happens
to the rope when you roll
the spool away from you.
Let's roll it a quarter turn.
So this is the distance
the spool has traveled
and it's equal to a quarter
of the circumference.
Now, in doing so, we have unspooled some of the rope.
How much rope have we unspooled?
Well, just this amount here
which is less than the distance
the spool has traveled.
In other words, we
haven't unspooled enough
of the rope to compensate
for the distance the spool has traveled.
The result is that the rope
is pulled from our hands.
The rope is pulled away from us.
That means if we do the opposite
and pull the rope towards us,
the spool should do the opposite as well
and roll towards us.
By the way, I'm assuming
that there is always
enough friction between
the spool and the table
so the spool always rolls
instead of slipping.
Interestingly, if I pull the rope upwards
then the opposite happens.
The rope gets longer as the
spool rolls away from me.
That means there must
be a point somewhere in
between vertical and
horizontal where the spool
neither rolls away, nor rolls
towards the pulling force.
Interestingly, the angle
of the rope doesn't just
affect the angle that
the force is applied.
It also affects the point on the object.
The force is applied to
like when I'm pulling vertically upwards
the force is being applied from here.
But when I'm pulling horizontally,
the force is being applied down here.
Look, as I change the angle of the rope,
there comes a point where the direction
of the force passes
through the pivot point.
And if the force is passing
through the pivot point,
then it can't be applying a turning force
around that pivot point.
So that's the magic angle.
I won't go through the mathematics
but here it is on the screen.
That's the angle at which the spool will
neither roll towards or away
and then it's impossible
to have enough friction.
The spool simply slides.
But what happens in the
limit as the spool fills
up with rope, when you've
got only a tiny gap
between the rope and
the edge of the spool,
like the spool is almost full,
you really do need to worry
about if there's enough
friction to avoid slipping.
So I'm using this high friction mat here
and I've switched to a less stretchy rope.
And just like with the sewing
thread for a really short tug
on the rope, the spool
travels a really long way.
I have some serious mechanical
advantage here, and actually
it's really easy to calculate
the mechanical advantage.
It's just the distance traveled
by the force divided by the
distance traveled by the load.
In this case, it's this distance
divided by this distance
which works out to be this
length divided by this length
which works out to be this radius divided
by itself minus this radius.
So if this radius is one
and this radius is very
nearly one like 0.9,
then you have a mechanical
advantage of 10.
Actually, it's the spool that
has the mechanical advantage
over me, right?
Because the spool has a low
force over a large distance.
Yeah, that's right.
My hand has a mechanical disadvantage
but it means I can get something
to move a long distance
by applying a large force
over a short distance.
And brilliantly, when you
fill the spool up completely
you get a singularity
in the equation for mechanical advantage.
Not a singularity in that sense
but a singularity in the sense
of like in this simplified
mathematical description
we get an infinity.
We have infinite mechanical advantage.
Obviously, you can't get
that in the real world.
Something has to fail
and the first thing to fail is friction.
In this case, we just end
up dragging the thing along.
But also when the spool is nearly full,
you hardly have to tilt the rope up at all
for the solution to flip
and the spool to roll away.
And it explains our
experience with toilet roll.
The spool of toilet roll is
by definition always full.
It's always being pulled from the edge
of the spool because the loose end
of the toilet roll is
the edge of the spool.
So what happens if you carry
on past the spool being full?
Well, in reality,
the rope itself would
become the outermost part
of the spool and you'd have
the toilet roll situation.
But what if you could
somehow keep the frame
of the spool on the ground so
that the rope was being
pulled from under the ground?
Basically, I just wanna see what happens
to the maths as this radius
gets bigger than this radius
without having to worry
about real world constraints
like the fact that rope
can't pass through a table.
Well, I can achieve that with this setup.
So this is now the radius of the spool.
The radius of the rope is greater
than the radius of the spool,
which is what we wanted
and it's able to pass through the table.
This clear acrylic is
now just there to hold
the rope in place.
It's not part of the spool geometry.
So will the spool roll towards me
or away from me when I pull on the rope?
Remember the two ways
of thinking about it.
You can consider this
to be the pivot point
and the force is being applied here.
Or you can think about what will happen
to the rope if I roll the
spool one way or the other.
So this time the spool rolls away
from me when I pull on the
rope and the rope gets longer.
Again, that makes sense from
a pivot point, point of view.
And if you think about what
happens when the spool rolls
towards you, well, this is
how far the spool travels
and this is how much rope you
are adding back to the spool.
In other words, the
rope is being taken away
from you more quickly than the
spool is coming towards you.
And again, the rope is
pulled away from your hands.
So if you do the opposite and
pull the rope towards you,
you should expect the spool
to do the opposite as well.
It's interesting to
note that in this setup,
the spool will always roll
to the right regardless
of the angle I choose,
whereas with this setup
there's an angle at which it flips.
And that makes sense
because in this setup,
the force vector never passes
through the pivot point.
There are two other limits to consider.
There's the limit as the spool
tends towards being empty.
And if we assume that there is
no central hole in the spool
then it's just being pulled
from the very center.
And if we assume that the
cord has no thickness,
then the infinitely thin central axis
of the spool will gather no cord.
In that scenario, the spool would travel
at exactly the same speed as
the hand pulling on the cord.
But what about taking
this setup to the extreme?
Just keep adding rope.
What happens in the
limit of infinite rope?
Well, that's a slightly
tricky thing to build
but what we're really saying
is what happens in the limit
as this radius becomes infinitely
larger than this radius
and we can achieve that
by seeing what happens as this
radius tends towards zero.
I 3D printed this
modification to give us a very
small spool radius, and what we notice is
that the spool hardly moves
at all, and that makes sense.
Every rotation of the spool
gives us loads of rope
but causes hardly any travel of the spool.
I really appreciate a
straightforward product pitch.
Like, here's a thing you
probably want to get done
but it'll take you ages to
figure out how to do it.
We've already figured it out.
We're super efficient at it.
Would you like us to do it for you?
And the sponsor of this video, Incogni,
fits that description perfectly.
So here's what Incogni offers.
There are these companies
called data brokers
that collect data about us
and then sell that data
to other companies.
We don't know who they're selling to
but we can contact them
and ask them to stop and delete our data.
The problem is there
are literally hundreds
of them and they all want to
be contacted in different ways.
Some want you to email, some
want you to fill in a web form,
some of them will reject your request
and you have to figure out how to appeal.
Incogni have figured out all
of that stuff already
and they've automated it.
So now you can sign up to Incogni,
give them the right to
work on your behalf,
and they just get to it
and you can see the
progress on the dashboard.
Look, these are all the
companies that now no
longer have my data, and honestly
one thing I really like
is that they're not
constantly banging on about
what they're doing for you.
They'll send you a
progress email once a week
if you want them to, or you can
just check on the dashboard.
What I've noticed now is
that I don't get any more
of those weird phone calls from
companies that I don't know
but that seem to know a lot about me.
And it's just one of those
things that I wanted to get done.
And now it's done.
If you're interested, the offer
on this one is really good.
The first 100 people to
go to incogni.com/science
and use promo code science
at checkout will get 60% off.
The link is also in the description
so check out Incogni today.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
If you did, don't forget to hit subscribe
and the algorithm thinks
you'll enjoy this video next.
(upbeat music)