- This is a polo mint,
the British equivalent
of a Life Saver under a microscope,
except it's a really weird microscope.
Honestly, I'm not sure
that you could even call it a microscope.
I just don't know how to
characterize this thing.
Look, here's a Lego brick,
and what about this thing?
What is this?
I'll tell you at the end
of the video if you want to
have a guess in the meantime.
What's weird about these images is
that there's no color information
or transparency information.
What we're seeing is just the shape.
In that way it's kind of reminiscent
of what you see under an electron microscope,
but actually this is a
normal sized Lego brick
and this microscope uses touch
and I got to play with one thanks
to the Sempre Group who
said I could come round
and have a play.
They're are distributor of
precision measurement instruments
in the UK, link to what
they do in the description.
They're not paying me to make this video
neither is the manufacturer of the device.
I just saw it out the corner
of my eye when I was walking
around the advanced engineering expo
and I went up to them and said,
can I make a YouTube video?
So thank you for saying yes.
It's a handheld device.
It's called Gel Site because
at the end there's this gel pad.
The gel is especially formulated so
that when you push an object into it the gel deforms so that it can get into all the tiny nooks and crannies of the object.
Just behind the gel, there's
a camera pointing at it
and crucially, there is
a ring of six lights.
What you see in the preview image
on the screen is just
what the camera sees when
only one of those lights is switched on.
And you can see how the
image changes as we cycle
through the six lights.
By illuminating the
deformed gel in this way,
the human visual system
can discern the shape
of the object using cues
about light and shade
and shadows and highlights.
It's a bit like whitewashing
the object because by doing so
you are removing all information
about color and transparency.
And you might think, well
what's the point of a microscope
that removes information?
Why don't we just stick with
a light-based microscope
and then we don't lose any information?
Well, it turns out that
with some clever mathematics
we can actually gain
information that we would never
have had access to with
a regular microscope.
And it's all to do
with those six lights
arranged around the gel pad,
like in the preview image where
only one light is turned on.
The human eye can
discern things like, well
this area is higher up than this area.
This area slopes down to the left.
This area slopes down
to the right and so on.
But could a computer
brain do the same thing?
Well, it turns out that
if you present the computer
brain with six images,
one taken with each of the
six different light sources
you can use a clever algorithm
to analyze those six images
and come up with a 3D model
of that object accurate to
plus or minus four microns
in the case of this device
which is way better than
the human brain can do.
It's called the photometric
stereo technique
and there are publicly
available papers on the subject
and then there's some
proprietary stuff on top
in the case of this
device, and you can see why
it would be desirable
to remove information
about color and
transparency from the object
before trying to run the
algorithm on the six images.
By removing all color information
we can say with certainty that this region
of the image is bright because
it's facing the light source.
This region of the image is
dark because it's facing away
from the light source, but
real life objects have light
and dark regions unrelated
to the lighting of the thing.
In principle, the algorithm
should be able to cope
with objects that have
light and dark regions
because after all, it's only looking
at the differences that it perceives
from the six different images
at each point on the object
unless part of the object is jet black
in which case it's jet black regardless
of what direction it's lit from.
But perhaps the most challenging thing for the algorithm is transparency, reflection, and glare
and the gel pad removes
all of those things.
I think there's an
interesting distinction here
between human brains and computer brains.
Like human brains can
discern 3D information
from flat images of things,
even when color, glare,
and transparency haven't
been removed from the object.
That's because the human
brain can draw on experience.
Like your brain recognizes this flat image
of a Lego minifigure head
as a Lego minifigure head,
your brain doesn't think,
oh this region is dark
because it's facing away
from the light source.
You know that it's the eyeball.
Perhaps one day with the
addition of machine learning
an algorithm like the one used
by Gel Site could discern 3D information
from objects that haven't had color glare
transparency and reflection removed
by training the neural
network on everyday objects
in the same way that our
brains have been trained
through our lives to recognize objects.
There's an interesting side note here
about the way human brains perceive depth.
Like the human brain perceives depth
in lots of different ways.
For example, by having two
eyeballs, the slight difference
in the two images that
each eyeball gets can be
used to extract information about depth.
Another example is parallax.
There's loads of different
ways we perceive depth
but one way that's relevant
to this video is using light cues.
We don't need to take six different images
of an object with a light source
in six different locations.
We can do it with just
a single light source.
But to do that, your brain
has to make an assumption
and every time your
brain makes an assumption
it can be tricked.
It can be tricked with
an optical illusion.
Take this image, for example.
It looks like a mountain of some kind
but if I turn it 180 degrees,
you can now see it's a crater.
It's called the crater illusion.
Your brain is tricked in this orientation
because it assumes the scene is lit
from the top down, and
that's a sensible assumption
given our every day experience.
Light typically comes from above us.
And the cool thing is you
can see the crater illusion
with these images.
Like here, the lettering
looks like it's sticking out
but that's only because
it's being lit from below.
By switching to the light at the top
you can see that the
lettering is in fact indented.
And of course, the crater
illusion disappears.
Where there are other
depth clues available
like no one would see this face as concave
even though it's lit from
below, because our experience
of faces gives us overriding
information about depth.
So what's this device actually used for?
Well, using the software
that comes with it
you can take actual measurements.
So you can see that the lettering
on this coin is raised by 70 microns
and this is really what
the device is all about.
It's handheld.
You can take it around with you
press it into things, and
as a manufacturer, let's say
you can figure out the tolerances
of the things you are
making in your factory.
You can also characterize a
surface and say how rough it is.
Another scenario is an
aircraft has a scratch
on the surface
and you need to characterize
the scratch to figure
out whether the aircraft can still fly.
Traditionally, you would create a cast
of the scratch and then
measure the cast in a lab, but
with this handheld device, you
can do it in a few minutes.
I asked them about drape because presumably there are parts of the object that the gel won't be able to get into.
So how does that affect
the use of the device?
- So we need the depth to
not be wider than the mark.
- Oh, okay.
- Say that was one millimeter
here and that was two.
What we would have is
the effect is we probably
get that deep.
We wouldn't get the corner.
But normally what the operator's looking
for is that value as opposed
to the the value of this area.
- So in terms of the application
- That's the important bit.
- Yeah, like the important bit
for me is, ooh, that looks pretty.
- That looks cool.
- Yeah yeah.
Here's some other cool things that we put
under the microscope.
This is some woven fabric
This is a UK driver's license
and you can see there's
a slight emboss here
which you can't see with the naked eye.
This is a button battery, and what I like
about this shot is that
there's a bit of hair
and dust stuck to the gel, so
you can see how the gel moves
and warps around the object
as you press into it.
Here's a phone speaker under
a microscope, and you can see
that the screen protector
isn't quite lined up.
Here's a chip and pin from a credit card.
This is interesting.
It's a part that I had 3D printed
and you can see how the
printhead must have moved
as it was printing the thing.
It goes around the edge
and then it fills in in
this kind of zigzag motion.
How cool is that?
Can you guess what this one is?
It's my stubble.
Sorry about that.
This is a love heart,
and this is the take home
message of the video by the way,
just be you.
The gel pads get sticky
over time and need to
be replaced periodically, but
when it's a little bit sticky
the visuals are really interesting.
I really think this needs a sound effect.
You know what I mean?
The sponsor of this video
doesn't want your money.
In fact, maybe it wants to give you money.
If you are graduating
from high school in 2023
and you have an interest in
maths and or computer science
or you know someone with that profile
then this is a really
interesting opportunity.
Jane Street is a company
that solves problems
in the financial world, and
for the second year in a row
they're offering a five
week summer program
for recent high school graduates.
It's called the Jane Street
Academy of Math and Programming.
It's in New York.
Not only is the program
completely free, but travel,
accommodation, and meals are paid for
and there's a $5,000 scholarship
for every participant.
It's an in-person program
offering an interactive
STEM curriculum, focusing on mathematics,
computer programming, data
analysis, and game theory.
The program is for 2023
high school graduates
with an interest in maths
and computer science who
have experienced barriers
to accessing advanced STEM
educational opportunities.
The deadline for applications
is the 15th of March
so check out the link in the description.
There's loads of information there.
There's an FAQ,
everything you need to
understand the program
and of course, a button to apply.
So check it out today.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
If you did, don't forget to hit subscribe.
Oh, and that thing from the beginning
it's the inside of a quartz analog watch.
(upbeat music)