- This mirror is convex and
concave at the same time.
So what's it like to
look into this mirror?
We all know what it's like
to look into a convex mirror,
like this security mirror.
It creates a sort of fisheye effect.
And if you've ever looked
into a makeup mirror,
you'll know what it's like
to see your reflection
from a concave surface.
It magnifies your face.
Or you know, just look at the
front and back of a spoon,
though it's interesting
that this concave mirror
magnifies your face, while this one
turns your face upside down.
We'll need to figure that out.
What I'm actually showing
you here is what it's like
to be a camera looking into
concave and convex mirrors.
But for this video, I
want you to experience
what it's like to be a person looking into
all these different types of mirrors,
so I stuck my phone to the inside
of this Arnold Schwarzenegger mask.
So this is what it's like
to be Arnold Schwarzenegger
looking into a concave mirror
and this is what it's like
to be Arnold Schwarzenegger
looking into a convex mirror.
But what's it like to
be Arnold Schwarzenegger
looking into a mirror that's convex
and concave at the same time?
What do I even mean by that?
Well, I'm talking about a
mirror that has a saddle point,
and just from the name, you
probably already have an idea
what I'm talking about.
I don't have a saddle for
illustration purposes,
but I do have a Pringle,
and a Pringle is a saddle,
from a mathematical point of view
and only a mathematical point of view.
This is the saddle point of the Pringle
and if you travel left or
right away from that point,
the height of the Pringle goes down.
In other words, the
saddle point is a maxima,
but if I rotate the
Pringle and do it again,
traveling left or right
away from the saddle point,
the height of the Pringle goes up.
In other words, this point is a minima.
So depending on which plane
through the Pringle you choose,
the saddle point is either
a maxima or a minima,
but when you take the shape as a whole,
it's neither of those things.
But for the purposes of
experiencing a mirror of this shape,
well, it's concave in this direction
and convex in this direction.
I was trying to figure out how the hell
do you make a saddle-shaped mirror,
and then I came across this video
on the AlphaPhoenix channel about putting
a mirrored surface on 3D
prints, so I asked him
if he'd be interested in
working on it together
and this is what he came up with.
Actually, it doesn't
involve 3D printing at all.
It's really clever actually,
and if you wanna find out
how it's done, I recommend
you watch his video
on the subject, but actually check out
the whole AlphaPhoenix channel,
because it's incredible.
The link is in the card
and the description there.
So this is what it's like
to be Arnold Schwarzenegger
looking into a saddle-shaped mirror.
As I rotate the mirror,
the direction of stretch
also rotates, but the image itself
never ends up inverted.
I found that quite surprising initially,
because the mirror's
concave in one direction,
and concave mirrors flip
images, but then I realized
this mirror is acting
like a makeup mirror.
The concave axis is magnifying the image
in that direction instead of flipping it.
So how can I get this
thing to act like a spoon
and invert the image in the concave axis?
Well, it's all to do with the
location of the focal point.
If the head is between the
mirror and the focal point
of the mirror, then the head is magnified.
If the focal point is between
the mirror and the head,
then the head is flipped.
With this mirror, the focal
point is somewhere out here,
and if I tried to film from
outside the focal point,
it just wouldn't work.
It's too small.
You wouldn't be able to see
any of Arnold Schwarzenegger.
So what I need to do is
bring the focal point
closer to the mirror.
In other words, I need
to make the curvature
of the mirror more
extreme, and fortunately,
this mirror is adjustable.
But then we run into a slight issue.
When you try to do that
with, say, a playing card,
you actually don't get a saddle point.
You get either a trough in this direction
or a trough in this direction,
and you can flip between the two.
If you try hard enough, you can end up
with this situation where two corners
are pointing up and two
corners are pointing down,
but then you've got this
flat region in the middle.
An acrylic sheet is more
elastic than a playing card,
so this isn't an issue
for shallow curvatures,
but when I try to increase the curvature,
you end up with one axis
more curved than the other
and you have this slight
flat region in the middle.
Andrew Dubinsky and
Michael Barson also offered
to make me a saddle-shaped
mirror and I'm hugely grateful
for what they've produced.
They used a different method.
The traditional way to make
a saddle point mathematically
is to construct a surface
called a hyperbolic paraboloid.
The equation for that
is Z equals X times Y,
which makes intuitive sense.
If X and Y are both
positive or both negative,
then Z is positive, which
pulls these two corners up,
but if X is positive and y
is negative or vice versa,
then Z is negative, which
pulls these two corners down.
But one thing that's really surprising
about a hyperbolic paraboloid is that
it can be constructed
using only straight lines.
You can see that here in these two sweeps.
Look, you've got straight
lines in this plane
and straight lines in this plane.
With that in mind, when Andrew and Michael
came across a bamboo
placemat, they realized
they might have the perfect beginnings
of a hyperbolic paraboloid mirror.
You see, the strips of bamboo constrained
those straight lines, but with a twist,
we can get that saddle point.
You can see here how they
created a cardboard frame
to lock it in the
saddle-point configuration.
Then by heating sheets of PETG above
the plastic transition temperature,
they could lay that over the
top and then clamp it down
with a similarly-manufactured top plate.
Once cooled, the sheet
of PETG would be smoother
than the surface it cooled on.
Then that became the surface that the next sheet is molded to.
Each step makes the surface
smoother and smoother
than the original bamboo,
and this is what we have.
So there's definitely a trade off
between these two methods of
making a saddle-shaped mirror.
You can achieve a greater
curvature with this one,
but it's a little more wobbly.
It's interesting to see how even very minor wobbles in the surface can distort the reflection so much.
I mean, I should've known,
that given that I made
two videos on the subject,
one about caustics
and one about Chinese magic mirrors.
Link in the card and the
description for them.
So now that the focal point is between
Arnold Schwarzenegger and the mirror,
look what happens when
I rotate the mirror.
The head ends up on its side at one point,
which is quite surprising.
When the mirror is positioned like this,
with that concave axis at 45 degrees,
then you're flipping the
image in this direction.
Look what happens when
I do that in Photoshop.
Here's the flip, and
that quite intuitively
puts the image on its side.
The mirror's convex in this direction,
so the image is squished
in this direction.
Shrinking the image in this direction
is what skews the image.
That focal point actually
does something brilliant
to the rays of light hitting the mirror.
Andrew and Michael used a laser line
and a fog machine to illustrate this.
See, there's a focal
point, but as you rotate
the laser line around, the focal point
kind of untwists itself as it moves
from the concave plane
to the convex plane.
How cool is that?
By the way, it's fiendishly
difficult to keep the subject
in the mirror when you're
watching a mirrored version
of your phone filming a mirror
that behaves differently
when you tilt it, depending on how it's oriented, and it's constantly overheating, because you've stuffed the head to stop it collapsing.
Which leads me to the
third saddle-shaped mirror,
which I commissioned animator
peak Pete McPartland to make.
With this, there's no
fiddling about with masks
and cameras and everything.
You just put a 3D model of a head in there
and stick the camera inside the head,
and I can easily adjust the
parameters of the mirror.
So there's lots to play with here,
but first, as this is rendered digitally,
we can explore a little bit of
the mathematics of the curve.
It's really cool to look at a
contour map of a saddle point.
Look, as I cut through the mirror,
these two curves are hyperbolas, and look,
when you get to this point, they touch
and you end up with a cross, and actually,
that's true of all saddle points.
Every saddle point has
contour lines that cross.
Interestingly, a hyperbolic
paraboloid can also
be formed with the
equation Z equals X squared
minus Y squared.
Look, you can see there's
the X squared curve
and there it is sweeping over
the minus Y squared curve.
So this is what happens
when you approach the mirror
but don't go past the focal point.
Your face basically stretches out.
Then if you carry on past the focal point,
your face unstretches again.
That's counterintuitive
to me, but actually,
if we rotate the mirror through 45 degrees
so that the concave axis is vertical,
we can see that the face
starts flipped top to bottom,
and when you pass through the focal point,
it comes back 'round to the right way up.
And so actually what you're
seeing in this orientation
is the face flipped
horizontally and then unflipping
when you go through the focal point.
You also see copies of the face
creeping in from the sides.
It might be more correct to
say that those side faces
replace the middle face, as opposed
to the middle face flipping,
and that's a brand new sentence
that's never been said before.
I used an iPhone to take a scan
of my face so I could
put that in the render.
It's not a great quality
model, but it's interesting
that you can use an iPhone's
face ID tech in this way.
Here's what happens when you
move your head up and down,
and when you move your head side to side,
and for completeness and because we can,
here's what happens when
the mirror slowly flattens
and then goes the other way.
Probably the ultimate
way to make a physical
saddle-shaped mirror would be with CNC.
There are some significant
complications with that.
A lot of it's to do with
the time and expense
of finishing the surface,
though because the saddle shape
is made of straight lines,
you could potentially
make this thing using wire EDM.
Link in the card and description
to my video about wire EDM.
But potentially you could
have a really nice surface
after the cut that doesn't need
a huge amount of finishing.
If that ever happens, I'll
make a follow-up video.
I will watch any movie
starring Arnold Schwarzenegger.
"Terminator," "Terminator 2," "Twins."
Here's the thing, though.
I've never seen "Conan the Barbarian,"
even though it's on
Netflix, and that's because
it's not on Netflix in the UK.
Brilliantly, if I search for,
"Conan the," Netflix shows me
this show called "Barbarians."
It knows what I want.
It's just not giving it to me.
But it is available in the U.S.,
so if I turn on a U.S.
location in Surfshark VPN,
the sponsor of this video, and then look,
I go back to Netflix, and
there's "Conan the Barbarian!"
Yay!
A VPN encrypts all the web
traffic leaving your device,
meaning that nobody on your Wi-Fi network,
nobody at your internet service provider,
nobody in your government,
if that's something
you need to worry about, is able to see
the websites that you visit.
Typically, they wouldn't
be able to see the content
of the websites you visit,
because most websites use HTTPS,
but they would still be
able to see the domain names
that you visit if you didn't use a VPN.
If that's important to
you, then that's another
use case scenario.
To flip the Netflix use case on its head,
I was in France recently and
it was a real pain in the arse
to do any kind of life
admin, because any website
that I visited while I was
there wanted to redirect me
to the French version, but
by switching Surfshark VPN
to a UK IP address, everything
worked as if I was at home.
That's just a couple of use cases.
What else to say?
Once Surfshark account can be used
on an unlimited number of devices.
There's a 30-day money back guarantee,
which means you can try
absolutely risk free.
If you're interested, then
there's a great promotion
on this one.
If you go to surfshark.deals/stevemould,
you'll get three extra
months absolutely free.
The link is also in the description,
so check out Surfshark today.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
If you did, don't forget to hit subscribe,
and the algorithm thinks
you'll enjoy this video next.
(funky jazzy music)