- There was a time when the universe was expanding
so rapidly that parts of it were moving apart
from each other faster than the speed of light.
That time is right now.
A lot of people make a big deal out of the
fact that during inflation, right after our
universe burst into existence, the whole universe
was expanding faster than light.
Now, while that is true, it kind of implies
that the universe doesn't normally do that,
and it does.
I mean, if you pick two points far enough
apart in our universe, you can always find
ones that are moving apart from each other
faster than light.
That is simply due to all of the expanding
space in between.
So our universe is now and has always been
expanding faster than the speed of light.
But doesn't this violate Einstein's special
theory of relativity that says nothing should
be able to move faster than light?
Actually, no.
Relativity says nothing can move through space
faster than light, but that doesn't stop space
itself from expanding however it likes.
Now, it was Hubble in the late 1920s who made
the observations of the night sky, which led
us to see that our universe is expanding.
The further out in space he looked, the faster
the objects were moving away from us.
So imagine a point so far out there that the
average recession velocity is the speed of
light.
I mean, if you think about it, it's going
to be the same distance in every direction.
So that would form a sphere which we call
the Hubble Sphere.
Everything beyond that sphere is moving away
from us faster than the speed of light.
So common sense would say we would never be
able to see the light from those objects because
of how fast they're moving away from us.
But in fact, this is not true.
We can see those objects.
To understand how this could work, picture
a galaxy beyond our Hubble Sphere.
It's receding faster than light, it's in a
super luminal region of space from our perspective.
So any light that emits in our direction,
will actually be moving away from us as time
goes on.
Well that doesn't sound very promising.
But due to the accelerating expansion of space,
our Hubble Sphere is actually getting bigger.
And if it gets bigger faster than that light
can get away, then at some point that light
is going to travel from a super luminal region
of space into a subluminal region of space,
and so it can start making progress towards
us.
So we can detect it, so we can see that distant
galaxy, which is of course now even further
beyond our Hubble Sphere, but we can see its
light.
We can detect that it's there.
This is remarkable.
In fact, all of the photons we now receive
from the first 5 billion years of the universe,
they were all emitted in regions of space
that were traveling, at the time, faster than
the speed of light relative to us.
The objects that emitted them were, are, and
always have been moving away from us faster
than the speed of light.
But their light has entered our Hubble Sphere
and had enough time to reach us, and so we
can see them.
So the observable universe is larger than
our Hubble Sphere.
It's actually limited by what's called the
particle horizon.
That is based on the amount of time light
has had to travel towards us since the beginning
of time, that is 13.8 billion years ago as
far as we can tell.
Now because the universe has been expanding
and that expansion has been accelerating,
things are much further out than 13.8 billion
light years away.
I mean, the observable universe has a radius
of over 46 billion light years.
The diameter is about 93 billion light years.
That is a huge volume of things that we can
see.
And 13.8 billion years ago, everything in
that volume and everything beyond it that
we can't see would have been compressed into
a tiny infinitesimally small point that we
call the singularity.
Actually, no.
I mean, that would be true if the universe
is finite.
But if the universe is infinite, and it kind
of looks like it is, then it was always infinite.
So the big bang would have happened literally
everywhere.
But if the universe has always been infinite,
then what is it expanding into?
Well, it doesn't have to expand into anything.
I mean, it can expand into itself.
That's the thing about infinity.
You never run out of it.
This episode of Veritasium was supported by
audible.com, a leading provider of audiobooks
with over 150,000 titles in all areas of literature,
including fiction, non-fiction, and periodicals.
This week I wanted to recommend the book Hitchhiker's
Guide To The Galaxy.
It's one of my favorites and it's a classic
of the science genre.
You know, people often ask me, why is the
number 42 on the Veritasium logo?
And that's because it's the answer to the
ultimate question of life, the universe, and
everything.
So if you haven't read this book yet, you
should definitely check it out, and in fact,
you can download it for free by going to audible.com/veritasium,
or you can pick any other book of your choosing
for a one month free trial.
So I want to thank Audible for supporting
me and I want to thank you for watching.