- [Derek] The modern era of electronics
began with the light bulb
but not in the way you might think.
Early light bulbs consisted
of a carbon filament
sealed inside a glass bulb
with a vacuum inside.
When a potential difference was
applied across the filament,
current flowed through it,
heating it up to over 2000 Kelvin,
so hot that it glowed.
If there had been much oxygen in the bulb,
the filament would've burned immediately.
That was the reason for the vacuum.
But from the perspective of electronics,
the real breakthrough came
from a curious observation
made by Thomas Edison.
He saw that over a bulb's lifetime,
the glass became discolored,
turning yellow, and then brown,
but only on one side.
So what was going on?
Well, the heated filament
emits not only light and heat
but also electrons.
You can think of them being
boiled off the surface
of the carbon.
This phenomenon, known
as thermionic emission,
had twice been discovered independently
by other scientists up
to 27 years earlier.
But after Edison, it became widely known.
In fact, for a time,
the emission of electrons
off a hot filament
was called the Edison effect.
Now, these electrons floating
around were unobstructed
because they're in a vacuum.
But since there was a potential difference
across the wires that led to the filament,
the electrons were attracted
to the positive wire.
So they accelerated towards it
and most would whizz straight past it
and crash into the glass,
over time discoloring it
only on the positive side.
I should note that Edison
was using DC electricity.
If he had been using AC,
then both sides would've been discolored.
But it was this observation
that set the scene
for an electronics revolution,
and eventually the
first digital computers.
In 1904, John Ambrose
Fleming patented a device
that was very similar
to Edison's light bulb,
but with one important addition:
a second electrode in the bulb.
By charging this plate positively
with respect to the filament,
electrons could be
accelerated across the gap,
completing the circuit.
But if the plate were slightly negative
relative to the filament,
then it would repel electrons
and no current would flow.
Fleming called his device a
one-way street for electricity.
Since only one of the
electrodes was heated,
electrons could only flow
from there to the plate
and not the other way around.
The device was called a thermionic diode
and it was used initially
for detecting radio signals
but it could also convert
alternating current to direct current.
Scientists quickly realized
that a more efficient design
had the filament in the center
and the other electrode
to the plate or anode
as a cylinder surrounding it.
This geometry captured
more of the electrons
coming off the filament
and allowed for larger currents to flow.
-  Oh, there she goes.
- [Derek] With just one of these diodes,
you could convert AC
into a bumpy kind of DC.
But combining a few diodes and a capacitor
led to a fairly steady direct current,
and this was a big deal.
It was the first practical
vacuum tube device
and the model for all vacuum tubes
that would dominate the industry
for the next half century.
In the early 1900s,
the big problem in
electronics was amplification.
Radio had just been invented
but its range was limited
by the lack of reliable equipment
that could boost weak signals.
Similarly, telephone calls were limited
to at most 1300 kilometers
because by that point,
the signal was two faint to hear.
Rudimentary form of
amplification had been built
for telegraph operation called the relay.
In a relay, there is an electromagnet.
And when current flows
through that electromagnet,
it attracts a switch,
turning on a second circuit.
But when the current through
the electromagnet stops,
the switch is released
and the second circuit is open again.
This device works well for amplifying
the dots and dashes of Morse
code along a telegraph line
but its binary output means it's incapable
of amplifying the complex
and analog signals
of phone calls and radio waves.
And that's why it was such
a breakthrough in 1906
when Lee de Forest took the diode
and added another electrode into the bulb.
This electrode wasn't
a solid piece of metal
but rather a sparse wire mesh
and it was positioned in
between the filament or cathode
and the anode.
With three electrodes,
it was called a triode.
Now, a large potential
difference could be applied
across the anode and cathode
but the number of electrons
that actually flowed between them
was controlled by the voltage on the grid,
as this new electrode was known.
If the grid were slightly
negatively charged,
it repelled electrons from the filament
so that none could flow
through to the anode.
But if the grid were slightly positive,
then electrons were attracted
away from the filament
and most of them would pass
through the holes in the grid,
and then accelerate to the anode.
So in this way, a small
change in voltage on the grid
can control a huge voltage at the anode
and the response is rapid.
So you can get high
frequency amplification.
I like to think of it
as standing at the top of a high cliff,
opening and closing a valve on a big water pipe.
I mean, it doesn't take much
energy to turn the valve
but that small input is converted
into a huge output of water
falling down the cliff.
- [Derek] You're powering
up this track here.
- [David] Warming up, you
can see it warming up there.
- [Derek] So the yellow is the input?
- [David] Yellow is the input.
Purple is the output.
We have essentially a two-volt change
on the input giving us, what is this?
Five volts, so five, 10,
15-volt change on the output.
- [Derek] For this demonstration,
we were only using 24 volts on the anode.
If we had used a higher voltage,
we could have got a lot more amplification
and people did.
This was the device that allowed us
to call long distance for the first time.
Using vacuum tubes,
the first transcontinental call
from New York to San Francisco
took place on the 25th of January, 1915.
- [Derek] Whoa.
- [David] Yeah, there we go,
should be 10 volts.
- [Derek] It's hard to see the grid here
because just like with
the cylindrical diode,
the best configuration for a triode
is to have a cylindrical configuration.
The anode is on the outside,
the grid is cylindrically inside that,
and the cathode or
filament is in the center.
The invention of the triode
was incredibly important.
Radios, TVs, whatever
electronics people had
were powered by vacuum tubes.
You would've had so many in your house
even up until the 1960s and '70s.
But vacuum tubes weren't done
revolutionizing electronics.
In his 1937 thesis,
Claude Shannon found a connection
between electric circuits
and a branch of mathematics
known as Boolean algebra.
Working in the mid-1800s,
George Boole was trying to find
a mathematical foundation for logic.
Under his system,
a true statement was represented
as a 1 and a false statement as a 0.
And Boole also developed
a few operations like AND.
If both statements A and B were true,
then the output would also be true.
What Shannon realized is
that Boole's operations
could be represented
as electronic circuits,
that there was an equivalence
between mathematical statements
and electric circuits.
All you needed to realize these
circuits in the real world
were a couple switches.
That same year, 1937,
George Stibitz built the
first digital calculator.
It could add two 1-bit binary numbers.
That is it could add two numbers
so long as they were either 0 or 1.
The calculator worked using a relay,
that electromechanical
switch from telegraphy.
There were two inputs.
If they were left open, the input was 0.
If closed, it was a 1.
The output was shown with two light bulbs.
If no lights were on,
the answer was 0.
If the output light was on,
the answer was 1.
And if the carry light was on,
the answer was a 2.
The circuit diagram works like this.
If neither switch A or B is closed,
so adding 0 + 0,
then no current flows through the circuit
and no light bulb would light up.
But if input A was closed,
the current would flow
through the solenoid,
creating a magnetic field
that pulls the switch inside it closed,
and this connects the
output light bulb to power
and disconnects the carry light bulb.
So the output light bulb lights up,
meaning that the answer is 1.
And the same thing would happen
when input B was closed and A was open.
But if you closed both
A and B simultaneously,
then there is no current
flowing through the solenoid
but there would be a current flowing
from the battery connected to A,
which is connected to
the carry light bulb.
So it lights up indicating 1 + 1 equals 2.
This is the beginning of the digital age,
and no it was not glamorous.
Stibitz built his device
out of a few batteries,
light bulbs, and relays
he had lying around.
And for the inputs, he
cut up a tin of tobacco.
He built it in one night
at his kitchen table
which is why it became
known as the Model K.
The circuit that Stibitz built
is now called a half adder.
But if you look at the circuit
through the eyes of Claude Shannon,
you realize it's actually
a pair of logic gates.
The output light bulb should turn on
when either A or B, but
not both, are closed,
so this is known as an exclusive OR gate.
Whereas the carry light
bulb should only turn on
when both A and B are closed,
so this is an AND gate.
This circuit uses electrical versions
of Boolean operators, XOR and AND.
And it's possible to build
other Boolean operators
as electronic gates
for things like OR, NOR, and NAND.
And you might say, what's the big deal?
I mean, the big deal is
that you just tricked
a bunch of electrons
into doing math for you.
Sure, it's very simple math,
but you could connect a bunch
of these half adders together
and build more and more
complicated circuits
that could do more complex math,
which is exactly what Stibitz
and his colleagues at Bell Labs did.
Two years later, they built the model I,
which had more than 400 relays
and could add two eight
digit numbers together
in a 10th of a second.
It could also multiply eight digit numbers
and do multiplication of complex numbers,
though these more complicated
operations took longer,
about a minute per calculation.
- So you put a voltage through a coil
and it'll turn that switch on or off.
So you've got your two operands here.
And if you wanna add two numbers together,
so 2 is this,
3 is this, right?
So 1, 0 is 2.
- [Derek] Yeah.
- [David] And 1, 1 is 3.
And so then when you want to calculate it,
you just hit the go button down here.
We get 101.
- [Derek] I love the sound of that.
That is amazing.
- It's magical, so if
you wanna do like say,
8 plus, that would be 4
so 8 + 8, I think, right?
- [Derek] Okay.
- [David] Yeah, 8 + 8,
that would be, 16, no,
it clears it on its own.
- [Derek] Okay.
- [David] There you go.
Eight plus eight is 16 in binary,
which would be 1 0 0 0 0.
(machine clacking)
This is essentially a
1-bit arithmetic unit.
There's no logic functions.
It only ever does add.
Now, let's say we wanna do 5 - 2,
the answer's gonna be 3.
So we flip this little switch here
that lets me know that I'm
doing a subtraction operation
and we do subtraction
by doing 2's complement.
So essentially what we're doing
is we're inverting one of the operands
and we're adding one.
So now when I run it,
(machine clacking)
we can see 5 - 2 is equal to 3,
so 2 and 1 is 3.
Now, because of the way that we do this,
the final carry flag
ends up getting illuminated
here on the end.
But if we know that we're
doing a subtraction operation,
we know that this final carry flag
is never going to be on otherwise.
- [Derek] Over the next 10 years,
they built six more
computers based on relays
which were used by the US military
and the National Advisory Committee
for Astronautics or NACA,
which later would become NASA.
But even by the early 1940s,
it was clear that the
mechanical nature of the relay,
the physical closing and
opening of the switches,
was too slow to be the future of computers
and they were also prone to breaking.
- Anytime you have
something that's mechanical,
it's gonna wear down.
Every time that relay switches,
there's a little bit of friction
on the rotation point inside of there
and there's contacts
that are making and breaking
electrical connections,
and those are gonna wear out.
- [Derek] And all the
relays opening and closing
meant that the computers
were incredibly loud.
(machine clacking)
- So it doesn't really work
in a business environment all that well.
You can't really stuff it into your office
that you're gonna drive people insane.
- [Derek] So what computer
scientists really needed
was an electronic switch
and that is where the
vacuum tube triode comes in.
Whoa!
I mean, sure it can work as an amplifier
if you put slightly positive
or negative voltages on the grid,
but it can also work as a switch.
If the grid voltage is very negative,
then no current flows.
And if the grid voltage is very positive,
then maximum current flows.
So a triode can be controlled
using no moving parts.
Just a voltage will set it
to be either a 0 or a 1.
And best of all, switching between the two
can be done rapidly with no noise
since you're just controlling electrons
zipping around in a vacuum.
This is the invention that took
computing to the next level.
The world's first electronic
programmable computer
was called ENIAC
and it came online for the first time
on December 10th, 1945.
It took up a whole room, weighed 30 tons,
and used 175 kilowatts of power.
So much that it led to a rumor
that every time it turned on,
the lights in Philadelphia,
where ENIAC was located, would dim.
Now, that was just a rumor,
but mainly because ENIAC
had its own dedicated electrical generator
to keep up with the enormous power draw.
Unlike previous computers,
ENIAC wasn't limited
to just solving one type
of mathematical problem.
It could be programmed and it was fast,
completing 500 operations per second.
At the time, the word computers
still referred to people
doing calculations with pen and paper.
So 500 operations per
second was really fast.
ENIAC's flexibility and power
was immediately useful
for the development of the hydrogen bomb.
The computations needed were so complex
that the director of
Los Alamos at the time
said that, "It would've been impossible
to arrive at any solution
without the aid of ENIAC."
- This is a hilarious part
bout having a processor
that is 1 meter tall
and 70 centimeters wide,
is that you can point at
actual parts of the processor.
- [Derek] This is what a 1-bit
vacuum tube computer looks like.
- [David] Can you feel
the heat coming off of it?
- [Derek] I certainly can.
- [David] I can feel the heat coming off.
- [Derek] It's getting warm.
- Well, I mean, 190 vacuum tubes is a lot.
I think we figured it out.
This is pulling like 350
or 400 watts of power
or something like that,
which is absurd.
At night, it's awesome.
It looks like a city.
- [Derek] But there were also major flaws
with vacuum tubes.
The filaments always needed to be heated,
so they used a lot of
power even when idle,
and they were big.
It was hard to make a glass vacuum tube
with complex electrodes
inside arbitrarily small.
They were also unreliable.
On average, a vacuum tube in ENIAC
broke down every few days.
And then, it needed to
be found and replaced.
The longest that ENIAC
operated for without failure
was just 116 hours.
The first digital computers
ran on glorified light bulbs.
That is why they were so big,
power-hungry, and unreliable.
The miracle and what has made
our modern lives possible
is that someone figured out
how to perform the same
trick with electrons
inside a solid piece of
material, in silicon.
But that's a story for another day.
If you wanna learn about
how modern computing devices
store and access information,
I highly recommend you check out
this video's sponsor brilliant.org.
They have courses on everything
from computer science fundamentals
to neural networks to quantum computing.
Their latest interactive course
is called How Technology Works.
It includes a lesson on computer memory
where you can get hands-on with the kinds
of computational logic gates
we discussed in this video.
It also has a lesson that
delves into the ingenious ways
video compression makes
modern day streaming possible,
so you can watch videos like this one.
Ever wondered how your
phone knows where you are?
There's a lesson on that too.
There's even a lesson on password theft
where you can walk in
the footsteps of a hacker
to discover why some passwords
are stronger than others.
You can try all these out for free
by going to brilliant.org/veritasium.
You know, whether it's
getting a working knowledge
of modern day technology
or building skills in math,
computer science or data science,
Brilliant is the best way to learn.
They have thousands of
bite-sized interactive lessons
that not only help master key concepts
but connect what you learn
to real-world examples.
And because each lesson is hands-on,
you'll build real intuition
so you can put what you've learned to use.
Now, as we've seen, the
development of technology
is an ongoing process
that constantly reshapes
the way we interact with
the world around us.
Today, it's more important than ever
to keep up with these changes.
Who knows what revolutionary
technology will emerge next?
But whatever it is, you can rest assured
that you'll be able to
learn about it on Brilliant.
And you can try everything
Brilliant has to offer for free
for a full 30 days.
Just go to brilliant.org/veritasium.
I will put that link
down in the description
and the first 200 of you to sign up
will get 20% off Brilliant's
annual premium subscription.
So I wanna thank Brilliant
for sponsoring this video
and I wanna thank you for watching.