- [Derek] This tiny robot mouse
can finish this maze in just six seconds.
(dramatic music)
Every year, around the world,
people compete in the
oldest robotics race.
The goal is simple:
get to the end of the
maze as fast as possible.
- The person who came second
(announcer chattering)
(people cheering)
lost by 20 milliseconds.
- [Derek] But competition
has grown fierce.
- When somebody saw my design,
they said, "You're crazy!"
- [Derek] Why is there so much
tension? What's riding on it?
Honor?
- Honor
(audience applauding)
(audience cheering)
- [Derek] This video is
sponsored by Onshape.
In 1952, mathematician
Claude Shannon constructed
an electronic mouse named
Theseus that could solve a maze.
The trick to making the mouse intelligent
was hidden in a computer
built into the maze itself,
made of telephone relay switches.
The mouse was just a magnet
on wheels, essentially,
following an electromagnet controlled
by the position of the relay switches.
- [Claude] He is now exploring the maze
using a rather involved
strategy of trial and error.
As he finds the correct path,
he registers the
information in his memory.
Later, I can put him down
in any part of the maze
that he's already explored,
and he'll be able to
go directly to the goal
without making a single false turn.
- [Derek] Theseus is often referred to
as one of the first examples
of machine learning.
A director at Google recently said
that it inspired the whole field of AI.
25 years later, editors at the Institute
of Electrical and Electronics
Engineers, or IEEE,
caught wind of a contest
for electronic mice,
or le mouse electronique,
as they had heard.
They were ecstatic. Were these the successors to Theseus?
But something had been
lost in translation.
These mice were just batteries in cases,
not robots capable of
intelligent behavior.
But the misunderstanding stuck
with them, and they wondered,
"Why couldn't we hold that
competition ourselves?"
In 1977, the announcement for IEEE's
Amazing Micro-Mouse Maze Contest
attracted over 6,000 entrants,
but the number of successful
competitors dwindled rapidly.
Eventually, just 15 entrants
reached the finals in 1979.
But by this point,
the contest had garnered
enough public interest
to be broadcast nationwide
on the evening news.
And just like the rumor that
inspired the competition,
Micromouse began to
spread across the world.
♪ Micromouse, is for the taking ♪
♪ Micromouse, is here and now ♪
♪ Take a chance, and start creating ♪
(upbeat music)
(reporter speaking Japanese)
- A Micromouse?
- [Group] Micromouse!
(audience applauding)
- Even people in the top two or three,
you can see them trying
to set their mice up,
and they can barely find
the buttons to press,
because it's absolutely nerve-racking.
(suspenseful music)
It doesn't matter what it
was, it could be horse racing,
it could be motor racing,
it could be mouse racing,
If you have a shred of
competitiveness in you,
you'd wanna win, right?
- [Derek] Just like a real mouse,
a Micromouse has to be fully autonomous.
No internet connection,
no GPS or remote control
and no nudging it to help it get unstuck.
It has to fit all its computing, motors,
sensors, and power supply in a frame
no longer or wider than 25 centimeters.
There isn't a limit on
the height of the mouse,
but the rules don't allow climbing,
flight, or any forms of combustion,
so rocket propulsion, for
example, is out of the equation.
(audience cheering)
(announcer chattering)
The maze itself is a square
about three meters on each side,
subdivided by walls into corridors
only 18 centimeters across.
And in 2009,
the half-size Micromouse
category was introduced,
with mice smaller than 12
1/2 centimeters per side,
and paths just nine centimeters across.
The final layout of the
maze is only revealed
at the start of each competition,
after which competitors are not allowed
to change the code in their mice.
(announcer speaking in Japanese)
(audience cheering)
The big three competitions,
All Japan, Taiwan, and USA's APEC,
usually limit the time
mice get in the maze
to seven or 10 minutes,
and mice are only allowed five runs
from the start to the goal.
- So if you spend a lot of time
searching, that's a penalty.
- Makes sense.
So the strategy for most Micromice
is to spend their first run
carefully learning the maze
and looking for the best path to the goal,
while not wasting too much time.
Then they use their remaining tries
to sprint down that path for
the fastest run time possible.
(audience applauding)
Solving a maze may sound simple enough,
though it's important to remember that,
with only a few infrared sensors for eyes,
the view from inside the
maze is a lot less clear
than what we see from above.
Still, you can solve a
maze with your eyes closed.
If you just put one hand along one wall,
you will eventually reach
the end of most common mazes.
And that's exactly what some initial
Micromouse competitors realized, too.
And after a simple wall-following mouse
took home gold in the first finals,
the goal of the maze was
moved away from the edges,
and free-standing walls were added,
which would leave a simple
wall-following mouse searching forever.
Your next instinct might
be to run through the maze,
taking note of every fork in the road.
Whenever you reach a dead end or a loop,
you can go back to the last intersection
and try a different path.
If your last left turn got you nowhere,
you'd come back to that
intersection and go right instead.
You can think of this strategy
as the one a headstrong mouse might use,
running as deep into the maze as it can,
and turning back only when
it can't go any further.
This search strategy, known
as depth-first search,
will eventually get the mouse to the goal.
The problem is, it might
not be the shortest route,
because the mouse only
turns back when it needs to,
so it may have missed a
shortcut that it never tried.
The sibling to this search
algorithm, breadth-first search,
would find the shortest path.
With this strategy,
the mouse runs down one
branch of an intersection,
until it reaches the next one,
and then it goes back to
check the path it skipped,
before moving on to the
next layer of intersections.
So the mouse checks
every option it reaches,
but all that backtracking
means that it's rerunning
paths dozens of times.
At this point,
even searching the whole
maze often takes less time.
So why not just do that?
A meticulous mouse could search
all 256 cells of the maze,
testing every turn and corner to ensure
it has definitely found the shortest path.
But searching so thoroughly
isn't necessary, either.
Instead, the most popular
Micromouse strategy
is different from all of these techniques.
It's a search algorithm
known as flood fill.
This mouse's plan is to make
optimistic journeys through the maze,
so optimistic, in fact,
that on their first journey,
their map of the maze doesn't
have any walls at all.
They simply draw the shortest
path to the goal and go.
When their optimistic plan inevitably
hits a wall that wasn't on their map,
they simply mark it down
and update their new
shortest path to the goal.
Running, updating, running, updating,
always beelining for the goal.
Under the hood of the algorithm,
what the Micromouse is
marking on their map
is the distance from every
square in the maze to the goal.
To travel optimistically,
the mouse follows the trail
of decreasing numbers down to zero.
Whenever they hit a wall,
they update the numbers on their map
to reflect the new shortest
distance to the goal.
This strategy of following
the numerical path of least resistance
gives the flood fill algorithm its name.
The process resembles
flooding the maze with water
and updating values based on the flow.
Once the mouse reaches the goal,
it can smooth out the path it took
and get a solution to the maze.
However, it may look back
and imagine an even shorter,
uncharted path it could've taken.
The mouse might not be satisfied
that it's found the
shortest path just yet.
While this algorithm isn't guaranteed
to find the best path on first pass,
it takes advantage of
the fact that Micromice
need to return to the start
to begin their next run.
So if the mouse treats its
return as a new journey,
it can use the return trip
to search the maze as well.
Between these two attempts,
both optimized to find
the shortest path from start to finish,
it's extremely likely that
the mouse will discover it,
and the mouse will have
done it efficiently,
often leaving irrelevant areas
of the maze entirely untouched.
Flood fill offers both an
intelligent and practical way
for Micromice to find the
shortest path through the maze.
Once there was a clear strategy
to find the shortest path,
and once the microcontrollers and sensors
required to implement it became common,
some people believed
Micromouse had run its course.
As a paper published in IEEE put it,
"At the end of the 1980s,
the Micromouse Contest
had outlived itself.
The problem was solved,
and did not provide any new challenges."
(people chattering)
In the 2017 All Japan
Micromouse Competition,
both the bronze-and silver-placing mice
found the shortest path to
the goal, and once they did,
they were able to zip along
it as quick as 7.4 seconds.
(audience applauding)
But Masakazu Utsunomiya's
winning mouse, Red Comet,
did something entirely different.
This is the shortest path to the goal,
the one that everyone took.
This is the path that Red Comet took.
It's a full 5 1/2 meters longer.
That's because Micromice
aren't actually searching
for the shortest path,
they're searching for the fastest path.
And Red Comet's search
algorithm figured out
that this path had fewer
turns to slow it down.
So even though the path was longer,
it could end up being faster.
So it took that risk.
(announcer speaking in Japanese)
(audience applauding)
- [Derek] It won by 131 milliseconds.
(upbeat music)
Differing routes at competition
are now more common than not,
and even just getting to
the goal remains difficult,
whether due to a mysterious algorithm
or a quirk of the physical maze.
(audience laughing)
- [Commentator] The corner,
it's a little bit like a...
Whoa!
(commentator speaking in Japanese)
- [Derek] Micromice don't
always behave as you'd expect.
(competitor speaking in Japanese)
(upbeat music)
Micromouse is far from solved,
because it's not just a software problem
or a hardware problem, it's both.
It's a robotics problem.
Red Comet didn't win
because it had a better search algorithm
or because it had faster motors.
Its cleverness came from how the brains
and body of the mouse interacted together.
- So it turns out solving
the maze is not the problem.
It never was the problem, right?
But it's actually about navigation,
and it's about going fast.
- Every year, the robots get
smaller, faster, lighter.
There is still plenty of innovation left.
And there's a small group of devotees in Japan busy building quarter-size Micromouse which would sit on a quarter.
busy building quarter-size Micromouse
which would sit on a quarter.
(commentator speaking in Japanese)
- [Derek] Nearly 50 years on,
Micromouse is bigger than ever.
(commentator speaking in Japanese)
(audience cheering)
- [Derek] Competitions
have appeared solved
at first glance before.
The high jump was an Olympic sport since 1896, with competitors refining their jumps using variations like the scissor, the western roll, and the straddle over the decades, with diminishing returns.
and the straddle over the decades, with diminishing returns.
But once foam padding became standard in competition,
Dick Fosbury rewrote the sport in 1968
by becoming the first Olympian
to jump over the pole backwards.
Now almost every high jumper does
what's known as the Fosbury flop.
If Micromouse had indeed
stopped in the 1980s,
the competition would've
missed its own Fosbury flops,
two innovations that completely
changed how Micromice ran.
After all, a lot can change
in a sport where competitors
can solder on any
upgrade they can imagine.
The first Fosbury flop
was one of the earliest
innovations in Micromouse,
and had nothing to do with technology.
It was simply a way of
thinking outside the box,
or rather, cutting through the box.
Every mouse used to
turn corners like this.
(Micromouse whirring)
But everything changed
with the mouse Mitee 3.
- So Mitee Mouse 3 implemented
diagonals for the first time.
(people chattering)
And that turned out to
be a much better idea
than we really thought.
And because it's cool, you know,
maze designers often put
diagonals into the maze now.
So, you know,
you could end up with a maze
where it never comes up,
but most of the time
it's actually a benefit.
- [Derek] In order to pull off diagonals,
the chassis of the mouse had to be reduced
to less than 11 centimeters wide,
or just five centimeters
for half-size Micromouse.
The sensors and software of
the mouse had to change, too.
When you're running
between parallel walls,
all you have to do is
maintain an equal distance
between your left and
right infrared readings.
But a diagonal requires
an entirely new algorithm,
one that essentially guides the mouse as if it had blinders on.
- Normally, if you're going
along the side of a wall,
or something like that,
most of the time you can
see the wall all the time.
And so that helps you to guide yourself,
and you know when you're getting off.
But in the diagonal situation,
you just see these walls coming at you.
- [Derek] And if you veer
even a tiny bit off course,
snagging a corner is a lot less forgiving
than sliding against a wall.
Diagonals are still one
of the biggest sources
of crashes in competition today.
But in exchange, a jagged path of turns transforms into one narrow straightaway.
transforms into one narrow straightaway.
- [Commentator] Oh!
Whoa!
(audience applauding)
(audience cheering)
- [Derek] These days, nearly
every competitive Micromouse
is designed to take this risk.
Cutting diagonals opened up
room for even more ideas.
Around the same time,
mice were applying similar
strategies to turning.
Instead of stopping and pivoting
through two right turns,
a mouse could sweep around
in a single U-turn motion.
And once the possibility
of diagonals were added,
the total number of possible
turns opened up exponentially.
The maze was no longer just
a grid of square hallways.
With so many more options to weigh,
figuring out the best path
became more complex than ever.
But the payoff was dramatic.
What was once a series of stops and starts could now be a single,fluid, snaking motion.
could now be a single,fluid, snaking motion.
How Micromice imagined
and moved through the maze
had changed completely.
(audience cheering)
Available technology was getting upgrades
over the years as well.
Tall and unwieldy arms that
were used to find walls
were replaced by a smaller array
of infrared sensors on board the mouse.
Precise stepper motors were traded in
for continuous DC motors and encoders.
- The DC motors give you more power
for less size and weight,
and so we were interested in doing that.
So then you have to have a servo.
You have to actually have
feedback on the motor
to make it do the right thing.
- [Derek] Gyroscopes added an
extra sense of orientation.
It's like a compass, if you
had this thing with you.
- They came about cause
of mobile phones, really.
so the technology provides people
with things which weren't there before.
All of the turning is
done based off the gyro
rather than counting
pulses off the wheels,
because it's much more reliable.
- [Derek] But even with all
the mechanical upgrades,
the biggest physical issue for Micromice
went unaddressed for decades.
One thing you'll see almost
every competitor holding
is a roll of tape.
Once you know to look for
it, you'll see it everywhere.
This tape isn't for repairs
or reattaching fallen parts.
It's to gather specs of dust
off the wheels in between rounds.
At the speed and precision
these robots are operating,
that tiny change in friction
is enough to ruin a run.
If you wanna turn while driving fast,
you need centripetal force to
accelerate you into the turn.
And the faster you're moving,
the more force you need
to keep you on the track.
The only centripetal force for a car
turning on flat ground is friction,
which is determined by two things,
the road pushing up the weight of the car,
or the normal force,
multiplied by the static
coefficient of friction,
which is the friction of the interface
between the tire and road surface.
This is why racetracks have banked turns.
The steep angles help cars
turn with less friction,
because part of the normal
force itself now points in
to contribute to the
centripetal force required.
If the banked turn is steep enough,
cars can actually make the turn
without any friction at all.
The inward component of the
normal force alone is enough
to provide the centripetal
force required to stay on track.
(upbeat music)
Micromice are no different,
and they don't have banked turns to help.
As they got faster and
faster, by the early 2000s,
their limiting factor was no longer speed,
but control of that speed.
They had to set their
center of gravity low,
and slow down during turns
to avoid slipping into
a wall or flipping over.
But unlike race cars, there
wasn't anything in the rules
to stop Micromouse competitors
from solving this problem
by engineering an entirely new mechanism.
Micromouse's second Fosbury flop
was almost considered a gimmick
when the mouse Mokomo08
first used it in competition.
You might be staring at
the video to try to see it,
but you won't.
Instead, it's something you'll hear.
(Micromouse whirring)
That isn't the mouse revving its engines.
It's spinning up a propeller.
And while flying over the
walls is against the rules,
there's nothing in the
rules against a mouse
vacuuming itself to the
ground to prevent slipping.
- Dave Otten was the first person
I saw put a fan on a mouse,
but he used a ducted fan,
and I think he was really looking
at kind of reaction force,
you know, blowing the thing down.
He had a skirt around, but it
was not terribly effective.
Forgive me for saying this, though.
The idea is to let as
little air in as possible.
And like your vacuum cleaner,
when you block your vacuum cleaner, right,
the motor unloads and speeds
up, and so the current drops.
But if you let too much air
in, the current's very high.
And these are just quadcopter motors,
and they draw a lot of current.
- [Derek] At the scale of
Micromouse, a vacuum fan,
often just built from
handheld drone parts,
is enough to generate a downward force
five times the mouse's weight.
Wow. Okay.
That's impressive.
So how much does the car actually weigh?
- About 130 grams.
And if you listen,
I don't know if you'll get
it on your microphone, but-
(motor whirring)
- Oh yeah.
- you can hear
the motors slow down, and it loads up.
- [Derek] With that much friction,
Micromice today can turn corners
with a centripetal acceleration
approaching six Gs.
That's the same as F1 cars.
(engines revving)
Once nearly everyone equipped fans,
the added control allowed builders
to push the speed limit on Micromice.
- When it's allowed to,
it will out-accelerate a Tesla Roadster,
but not for very far.
(Derek laughs)
- [Derek] And they can zip along
at up to seven meters per second,
faster than most people can run.
(audience laughing)
(Micromouse whirring)
(audience cheering)
Every one of the features now standard
on the modern Micromouse
was once an experiment,
and the next Fosbury flop
might not be far off.
The first four-wheeled Micromouse
to win the All Japan
competition did so in 1988,
but it would take another 22 years
of the winning mouse growing
and losing appendages
before four-wheeled mice became the norm.
With Micromice still experimenting
in six- and eight-wheel designs,
omnidirectional movement,
and even computer vision,
who knows what the next
paradigm shift will be?
- [Commentator] Your time
on the maze actually begins
only when you leave the start square,
so he's not penalized
for any of this time.
- [Derek] But if you wanna
get started with Micromouse,
you don't need to worry about
wheel count or vacuum fans,
or even diagonals.
- It is, to my mind,
the perfect combination
of all the major disciplines that you need
for robotics and
engineering and programming,
embedded systems,
all wrapped up in one accessible bundle
that you can do in your living room,
and you don't need a laboratory to run it.
You come along because you're
curious, and then you think,
"I could do that. That
doesn't look so hard."
And then you're doomed, really.
If it sucks you in, it turns
into quite the journey.
(commentator speaking in Japanese)
(audience cheering)
- [Derek] At its core,
Micromouse is just about a
mouse trying to solve a maze.
Though, nearly 50 years later,
it's a simple problem
that's a good reminder,
there is no such thing
as a simple problem.
♪ Micromouse, is for the taking ♪
♪ Micromouse, is here and now ♪
♪ Take a chance, and start creating ♪
♪ Micromouse, will show you how ♪
(logo beeping)
- If you wanna build your own Micromouse,
you'll likely need to design parts
using a 3D CAD program like Onshape,
the sponsor of this video.
Onshape is a modern CAD plus PDM system
designed for businesses,
and completely free for
makers and hobbyists to use.
Any serious hardware product
needs a precise design
in order to be successfully
made in the real world,
from a Micromouse model like this one
to a professional V2
engine model like this one.
Unlike traditional CAD programs,
which are installed on premises,
Onshape was built entirely in the cloud,
which allows engineering and design teams
to collaborate like never before.
Onshape allows you to
work together in real time
on the same design with multiple users,
just like Google Docs.
This completely eliminates the need
for emailing large files back and forth
and trying to keep track of who
has the most recent version,
whether it's V2 or V22.
With Onshape, Agile methodologies
that are common in software development
are now being adopted
in hardware development
to allow companies to build
better products faster.
Onshape's not only great for businesses,
but also for open source projects,
or just working on
designs with your friends.
Again, it's totally free for hobbyists,
so you can try it out for
yourself as much as you like
at onshape.pro/veritasium.
You can take Onshape
with you wherever you go.
You don't need a powerful desktop
or a specific operating system to run it.
Whether you're on a Mac or PC,
or even just on your phone,
you can easily use Onshape.
So to get started, sign up for free
at onshape.pro/veritasium.
I wanna thank Onshape for
sponsoring this video,
and I wanna thank you for watching.