This will revolutionize education.
No prediction has been made as often or as
incorrectly as that one.
In 1922, it was Thomas Edison who declared
that, “The motion picture is destined to
revolutionize our educational system and that
in a few years, it will supplant largely,
if not entirely, the use of textbooks.”
Yeah.
And you know how that worked out?
By the 1930s it was radio.
The idea was you could beam experts directly
into classrooms, improving the quality of
education for more students at lower cost.
And that would mean you require fewer skilled
teachers, a theme common to all of the proposed
education revolutions, like that of educational
television in the 1950s and 60s.
Studies were conducted to determine whether
students preferred watching a lecture live,
or sitting in an adjacent room where the same
lecture was broadcast via closed circuit TV.
What would you prefer?
In the 80s there was no debating.
Computers were the revolutionary solution to our education woes.
They were audiovisual, interactive, and could
be programmed to do almost anything you like.
Well at the time, they could run Oregon Trail.
But their potential was obvious.
Researches suspected that if they could teach
kids to program, say how to move a turtle
around a screen, then their procedural reasoning
skills would also improve.
So how did it go?
Well the students got better at programming
the turtle, but their reasoning skills were
unaffected.
Even by the 1990s we had not learned from
the failure of our past predictions and I
quote, “The use of videodiscs in classroom
instruction is increasing every year and promises
to revolutionize what will happen in the classroom
of tomorrow.”
Videodiscs?
Yeah, those giant oversized CD things.
Remember when they revolutionized education?
Nowadays plenty of things are poised to revolutionize
education like, smartboards, smartphones,
tables, and M.O.O.C.s.
Those are massive open online courses.
And some belief we’re getting close to universal
teaching machine, a computer so quick and
well-programmed that it’s basically like
having your own personal tutor in a machine.
Do these claims sound familiar?
Over the past 100 years, a lot of areas of
life have been revolutionized, but education
is not one of them.
By in large, students are still taught in
groups by a single teacher.
And that is not what a revolution looks like.
Some might blame this state of affairs on
the inertia of our educational institutions.
It’s just too hard to get a huge bureaucracy
to change.
But I think the reason technology hasn’t
revolutionized education is something else,
something that goes to the very heart of what
education is.
Let’s consider the process of learning.
Say you want to teach someone how a human
heart pumps blood.
Which learning aid do you think would be more
effective, this animation with narration or
this set of static picture with text?
Obviously the animation is better.
I mean for one thing it shows exactly what
the heart does.
For decades, educational research focused
on questions like this.
Does a video promote learning better than
a book?
Are live lectures more effective than televised
lectures?
Is animation better than static graphics?
In all well-controlled studies, the result
is no significant difference.
That is, so long as the content is equivalent
between the two treatments, the learning outcomes
are the same with all different media.
How is this possible?
How can something which seems so powerful,
like animation, be no more effective than
static graphics?
Well for one thing, animations are fleeting
and so you might miss something as they go
by.
Plus, since the parts are animated for you,
you don’t have to mentally envision how
the parts are moving.
And so you don’t have to invest as much
mental effort which would make it more memorable.
In fact, sometimes static graphics perform
better than animations.
And I think this points to a really fundamental
aspect of education which is, it doesn’t
matter what happens around the learner.
We are not limited by the experiences we can
give to students.
What limits learning is what can happen inside
the student’s head.
That is where the important part of learning
takes place.
No technology is inherently superior to any other.
Researchers spent so much time investigating
whether one medium or technology was more
effective than another that they failed to
investigate exactly how to use the technology
to promote meaningful thought processes.
So the question really is what experiences
promote the kind of thinking that is required
for learning?
Recently, that research is being conducted
and we’re finding out some pretty important
stuff.
I mean it may seem obvious, but it turns out
learning with words and pictures together,
whether they’re animation and narration
or static pictures and text, works better
than words alone.
Also, we see that anything which is extraneous
needs to be eliminated from a lesson.
For example, on-screen text competes with visuals, so learners perform better when it is omitted than when it is present.
Now that we know how best to make educational
videos, and any experience can be simulated
in the video setting, YouTube must be the
platform that will revolutionize education.
I mean the number of educational videos on
YouTube is increasing every day.
So why do we need teachers?
Well, if you think that the fundamental job
of a teacher is to transmit information from
their head to their students’, then you’re
right, they are obsolete.
I mean, you probably imagine a classroom where this teacher is spewing out facts at a pace which is appropriate for one student, too fast for half, and too slow for the rest.
Luckily the fundamental role of a teachers
is not to deliver information.
It is to guide the social process of learning.
The job of a teacher is to inspire, to challenge,
to excite their students to want to learn.
Yes, they also do explain and demonstrate
and show things, but fundamentally that is
beside the point.
The most important thing a teacher does is
make every student feel like they are important,
to make them feel accountable for doing the
work of learning.
All of this is not to say technology has had
no impact on education.
Students and teachers work and communicate
via computers.
And videos are used both inside and outside
of classrooms.
But all of this is best characterized as an
evolution, not a revolution.
The foundation of education is still based
on the social interaction between teachers
and students.
For as transformative as each new technology
seems to be, like motion pictures or computer
or smartboards, what really matters is what
happens inside the learner’s head.
And making a learner think seems best achieved
in a social environment with other learners
and a caring teacher.