- Right now some nation states
and individual actors are
intercepting and storing lots
of encrypted data like
passwords, bank details,
and social security numbers.
But they can't open these files.
So why are they doing it?
Well, because they believe that within
the next 10 to 20 years,
they will have access
to a quantum computer
that can break the encryption in minutes.
This procedure is known
as Store Now, Decrypt Later or SNDL.
And it works because there
is information around today
that will still be valuable in a decade.
Things like industrial and
pharmaceutical research
and top secret government intelligence,
and everyone is aware of this threat.
The National Security Administration
says that a sufficiently
large quantum computer,
if built would be capable of undermining
all widely deployed public key algorithms.
- You know in a five to 10 year timeframe,
quantum computing will break
encryption as we know it today.
- Even though sufficiently
powerful quantum computers
are still years away,
they're already a threat because
of Store Now Decrypt Later,
which is why the US Congress
just passed legislation
mandating all agencies start transitioning
right now to new methods of cryptography
that can't be broken by quantum computers.
You know, our current encryption schemes
have been remarkably successful
working effectively for over 40 years.
Up until the 1970s, if
you wanted to exchange
private information with someone,
you would first have to meet up in person
and share a secret key.
This same key would be used to
encrypt and decrypt messages.
So it's known as a
symmetric key algorithm.
As long as no one else gets
their hands on the key,
your messages are safe.
But now what if you wanna send information
to someone you've never met,
and it's too hard to arrange
an in-person meeting.
You can't share a key
over an unsecured channel
like a phone line or the mail,
because it could be intercepted.
And this is what in 1977,
led three scientists,
Riverst, Shamir, and Adelman
to come up with an
encryption breakthrough.
Today it's known by their initials RSA,
and it works something like this.
Every person has two
really big prime numbers,
all their own which they keep secret.
They multiply these numbers together
to get an even bigger number,
which they make public
for everyone to see.
Now, if I wanna send
someone a private message,
I use their big public number to garble my message.
And I garble it in such a
way that it is impossible
to ungarble without knowing
the two prime factors
that made that number.
This is an asymmetric key system,
since different keys are used to encrypt
and decrypt the message.
So it's easy for my intended
recipient to decode,
but impossible for everyone else,
unless they can factor
that large public number.
Now, someone could try to factor
it, using a supercomputer,
in the best known factoring algorithm
the General Number Field
Sieve, but modern cryptography
uses prime numbers that
are around 313 digits long.
Factoring a product of
two primes this big,
even with a supercomputer,
would take around 16 million years,
but not on a quantum computer.
See, in normal computers, a bit can only
be in one state at a time,
either a zero or a one.
So if you had two bits, they could be
in one of four possible
states, 00, 01, 10 or 11.
Let's say each of these
states represents a number,
0, 1, 2, or 3.
If we want to do a calculation,
for example, raising seven
to the power of one of these numbers,
we can only do it for one state at a time,
in this case seven squared
and so we get the answer 49.
Quantum computers consist of qubits
which also have two states, zero or one.
But unlike a classical bit, a qubit,
doesn't have to be in
just one state at a time.
It can be in an arbitrary
combination of those states,
a superposition if you
will, of zero and one.
So if you have two qubits,
they can exist simultaneously
in a superposition of 0, 1, 2, and 3.
Now, when we repeat the same calculation,
it will actually perform the calculation
for all of those numbers at the same time.
And what we're left
with is a super position
of the different answers.
1, 7, 49 and 343.
If we add another qubit,
we double the number of possible states.
So with three qubits, we
can represent eight states,
and thus perform eight
calculations all at once.
Increase that number to just 20 qubits,
and you can already represent
over a million different states,
meaning you can simultaneously compute
over a million different answers.
With 300 qubits, you can
represent more states
than there are particles
in the observable universe.
This sounds incredibly powerful and it is,
but there is one very big catch.
All of the answers to the
computation are embedded
in a superposition of states,
but you can't simply read
out this superposition.
When you make a measurement,
you only get a single value
from the superposition
basically at random,
and all the other information is lost.
So in order to harness the
power of a quantum computer,
you need a smart way to convert
a superposition of states
into one that contains only
the information you want.
This is an incredibly difficult task,
which is why for most applications,
quantum computers are useless.
So far, we've only
identified a few problems,
where we can actually do this,
but as luck would have it,
these are precisely the problems
that form the foundation
of nearly all the public key
cryptography we use today.
In 1994, Peter Shor and
Don Coppersmith figured out
how to take a quantum Fourier transform.
It works just like a
normal Fourier transform,
apply it to some periodic signal,
and it returns the frequencies
that are in that signal.
Now this may not seem
particularly interesting
but consider this.
If we have a superposition
of states that is periodic,
that is the terms in the
superposition are separated,
by some regular amount,
well we can apply the
quantum Fourier transform
and will be left with states
that contain the frequency of the signal.
So this we can measure.
The quantum Fourier transform,
allows us to extract frequency information
from a periodic superposition,
and that is gonna come in handy.
So how does a quantum
computer factor the product
of two primes much faster
than a conventional computer?
I want to explain this by first walking
through a simple example with
no quantum computer required,
and then I'll show how a quantum computer
could execute this method
even for a very large number
in a short period of time.
So let's say we have a number N,
which is the product
of two primes, p and q.
For the sake of this example,
let's set N equal to 77.
Now I bet you can guess the prime factors,
but let's pretend for the
moment that we don't know them,
because with a product of
really big primes, we wouldn't.
Now I want to use a fact about numbers
that feels like magic.
Pick a number g that doesn't
share any factors with N.
If you multiply g by itself
over and over and over,
you will always eventually,
reach a multiple of N plus one.
In other words, you can
always find some exponent r,
such that g to the power of r,
is a multiple of N plus one.
Let's see how this works.
Pick any number that is smaller than 77.
I'll pick the number eight.
This number doesn't share factors with 77.
And if you were doing
this with big primes,
it would also be extremely unlikely
that you just happen to pick a number
that shares factors with N.
Now multiply eight by itself
once, twice, three times
four times, and so on, raising
eight to ever higher powers
and then divide each
of these numbers by 77.
We're not really interested
in how many times
77 goes into the number,
just the remainder,
what's left over, because at some point,
77 should divide one of these numbers
with a remainder of exactly one.
So eight divided by 77 is
zero with a remainder of 8,
64 divided by 77 is zero remainder 64.
512 divided by 77 is six remainder 50.
And as we keep going, we get remainders
of 15, 43, 36, 57, 71,
29, and finally one.
So there we have it,
eight to the power of 10
is one more than a multiple of 77.
So we've found the exponent R
that satisfies this equation.
But how does this help
find the factors of N?
Well, we rearrange the equation
to bring one over to the left hand side,
and then we can split it
into two terms like so.
And now as long as r is
even, we have one integer
times another integer is
equal to a multiple of N.
This looks remarkably similar
to p times q equals N.
I mean since we know that p and q
are on the right hand
side of this equation,
they must also be on the left hand side
just multiplied by some
additional factors.
So one way to think
about what we've done is
we've taken a bad guess
for one of the factors G,
and by finding the exponent r,
we've turned it into
two much better guesses
that probably do share factors with N.
Since r was 10, the two terms
on the left hand side are eight
to the power of five plus one, 32,769
and eight to the power of
five minus one, 32,767.
These two numbers probably
share factors with N.
So how do we find them?
We use Euclid's algorithm.
If you wanna find the
greatest common divisor
of two numbers, say 32,769 and 77,
divide the bigger number
by the smaller one
and record the remainder.
In this case, 32,769 divided
by 77 gives a remainder of 44.
Then shift the numbers one
position left and repeat.
So now we divide 77 by 44
and we get a remainder of 33.
Repeat the process again.
44 divided by 33 gives a remainder of 11
and again 33 divided by 11
equals three remainder zero.
When the remainder is zero,
the divisor is the greatest common factor
between the two numbers you started with.
In this case, it's 11,
which is indeed a factor of 77 and 32,769.
You could do the same procedure
with the other number or just
divide 77 by 11 to get seven,
its other prime factor.
So to recap, if you wanna
find the prime factors p and q
of a number N, first, make a bad guess, g,
second, find out how many
times r you have to multiply g
by itself to reach one
more than a multiple of N.
Third, use that exponent to calculate
two new numbers that probably
do share factors with N.
And finally use Euclid's algorithm
to find the shared factors
between those numbers and N,
which should give you p and q.
Now, you don't need a quantum computer
to run any of these steps,
but on a classical computer,
this method wouldn't be any
faster than other methods.
The key process that a
quantum computer speeds up
is step two, finding the
exponent you raise G2
to equal one more than a multiple of N.
To see why, let's go back to our example,
where eight to the power of 10 is
one more than a multiple of 77.
Watch what happens to the remainders
if we keep going past
eight to the power of 10,
to 8 to the 11, eight
to the 12, and so on.
Well, we get remainders
of 8, 64, 50, 15, 43, 36,
57, 71, 29, and again one.
The remainders cycle and
they will just keep cycling.
Notice how the exponent
that yields a remainder
of one is 20, which is 10
more than the first exponent
that yielded a remainder of one.
So we know that eight to the 30
and eight to the 40, 8
raised to any power divisible
by 10 will also be one
more than a multiple of 77.
It's also worth noting that
if you pick any remainder
say 15, the next time you
find that same remainder,
the exponent will have increased by 10.
So you can find the
exponent R that gets us
to one more than a multiple of n,
by looking at the spacing of
any remainder, not just one.
Remember that.
Here I'm plotting out the
remainders on a log scale
so you can see they are
periodic with a period of 10.
If I had made a different guess,
say I had picked G equals
15 instead of eight,
well then the period would be different
and the remainders would be different
but there would always
be a remainder of one.
Why is this?
Well, now that you can see
this is a repeating pattern,
we can go back to the beginning
and any number raised to
the power of zero is one.
So that is actually the first remainder.
So it must also appear when
the cycle starts again.
Now we are ready to use a quantum computer
to factor any large product of two primes.
First we split up the
qubits into two sets.
The first set we prepare
in a superposition of zero
and one and two and three
and four and five and six
and seven and eight and nine,
all the way up to 10
to the power of 1,234.
Yeah, this is a huge superposition,
but if we had perfect qubits,
it would require only around 4,100.
The other set contains a
similar number of qubits
all left in the zero state for now.
Now we make our guess G,
which most likely doesn't
share factors with N.
We raise G to the power
of the first set of qubits
and then we divide by N
and store the remainder in
the second set of qubits
leaving the first set of qubits as it was.
Now we have a superposition
of all the numbers
we started with and the
remainder of raising G
to the power of those
numbers divided by N.
And through this operation,
we have entangled our two sets of qubits,
but we can't just measure
this superposition.
If we did, we would get a
random value and learn nothing.
But there is a trick we can use.
If we don't measure the
entire superposition,
but only the remainder part,
we will obtain some random remainder.
But this remainder won't occur just once.
It will occur multiple times
every time it comes up in the cycle.
Imagine we were doing
this with the example
from before with N equals
77 and G equals eight.
If the remainder we measured was say 15,
then there would be multiple
terms in our superposition.
Because there are multiple exponents
you can raise G2 that
give this same remainder,
exponents 4, 14, 24, 34, and so on.
They are each separated by 10,
and that value is the exponent
that satisfies our equation.
So more generally after
measuring the remainder,
we will be left with a
superposition of states
that all share the same remainder
and the exponents will all be separated
by the same amount r.
This is the number we are looking for.
Since the remainder is now
the same for all states,
we can put it to the side
and we now have a
superposition that is periodic.
Each term is separated from
its neighbors by an amount R.
If we now apply the
quantum Fourier transform
to this superposition of states
and I'm simplifying a little here,
we will be left with states
containing one over R.
So all that's left to do now
is perform a measurement
and find R by inverting it,
and that's it for the quantum part.
Now, as long as r turns out to be even
we can use r to turn our bad guess g
into two numbers that
likely share factors with N.
And as long as these terms themselves
are not a multiple of N,
we can use Euclid's algorithm
to find the factors of N
and break the encryption.
This would only take several
thousand perfect qubits,
but the qubits we have
today are imperfect,
so we need additional qubits
to act as redundant information.
In 2012, it was estimated
that it would take a
billion physical qubits
to break RSA encryption,
but by five years later that number
had dropped to 230 million.
And in 2019, after more
technological breakthroughs,
that estimate plummeted to just 20 million physical qubits.
So how many qubits do we have today?
Well, if we look at the state
of IBM's quantum computers,
we are nowhere near that number of qubits,
but progress looks to be exponential.
So now it's just a question
of when these two curves will collide
before all our existing public
key encryption can be broken.
Because we've long known
this threat is coming,
scientists have been looking
for new ways to encrypt data,
which can withstand attacks
from both normal and quantum computers.
In 2016, the National Institute
of Standards and Technology
or NIST, launched a competition
to find new encryption algorithms
that aren't vulnerable
to quantum computers.
Cryptographers from all over the world
submitted 82 different proposals,
which were rigorously
tested, some were broken.
And then on July 5th, 2022,
NIST selected four of
the algorithms to be part
of their post-quantum
cryptographic standard.
So how do they work?
Well, three of the algorithms are based
on the mathematics of latices.
So let's do a simple
example in the 2D plane.
Take two vectors, r1 and
r2, by adding together
different integer combinations
of these vectors, say three
times r1 and one times r2,
you can get two different points
and all the points you can get
to by combining these two vectors
in different ways is
what is called a lattice.
Now I will also give you the point C,
and your task is to tell me
which combination of r1 and r2
will bring me to the
lattice point closest to c.
It's pretty easy to see
that we can get there
by going in the direction of r2 twice
and in the negative direction of r1 twice.
Simple enough.
But those vectors, r1 and r2 are not
the only vectors that can
give you this lattice.
Take b1 and b2 for example.
These vectors also build
up the same lattice.
And now if I ask you
the same question again,
can you tell me the
combination of b1 and b2
that gets you to the
lattice point closest to c?
This has become a lot
harder, but why is that?
Each time we're taking a step,
we're trying to get closer
in either the X or Y direction,
but with the b vectors,
each time we take a step
in the right direction
with one vector, it puts us
off in the other direction.
And that's why these vectors
are a lot harder to work with.
In the end, it takes us a combination
of eight times b1 and
negative six times b2
to get to the closest lattice point.
That is a lot harder than before,
but it's still a relatively
easy problem to solve.
But if we extend it to three dimensions,
this already becomes a lot harder,
especially because you're
not given the collection
of all lattice points.
You're only given the
vectors that make it up.
So when you find a lattice
point close to the target,
you must still find all the
other lattice points near it
to make sure yours is indeed the closest.
Let's take a circle of
radius r in two dimensions.
The number of lattice
points inside the circle
is proportional to r squared.
Add a third dimension
and the number of points
in the sphere is proportional to r cubed.
So just watch how the number
of lattice points grows
as we increase the number of dimensions.
Solving the closest vector problem
is a piece of cake for your
computer in three dimensions.
Even a hundred dimensions
should be manageable.
But in proposed future encryption schemes,
we'll use around a thousand dimensions.
Take one step in the right direction
on one of those dimensions,
and you could potentially
be taking a wrong step in
the other 999 dimensions.
You win some, you lose everything else.
With that many dimensions,
it becomes extremely hard
to find the closest point
even for the most powerful computers,
that is unless you know
a good set of vectors.
So how do we use that to encrypt data?
Well, let's go back to our
two-dimensional example.
Each person has a good set of vectors
that describes a lattice,
but they keep these vectors secret,
and they only share their lattice publicly
using a set of vectors
that is hard to work with.
Now, if I want to send someone a message,
I pick a point on their
lattice, for example,
say this point corresponds
to the number seven.
So if I wanna send the number
seven, I can take that point
but then add some random noise to it.
So the message I send is not precisely
at that point but close to it.
Now, to decode the message,
my recipient must figure out
which lattice point is
closest to the message point.
In a thousand dimensions,
this will be extremely hard to do
unless you have the nice set of vectors,
which my recipient does.
So it's easy for the recipient,
who has the good vectors,
but hard for everyone else.
And as far as we know,
this problem is extremely
difficult to solve for both
normal and quantum computers.
Behind the scenes, there's
an army of researchers,
mathematicians, and cryptographers,
we're gonna make sure your
secret data stays secret.
These are some of the unsung heroes
that will keep us safe moving forward,
avoiding mass surveillance by governments
keeping critical infrastructure protected
and allowing you to live
as if quantum computers
were never invented in the first place.
(digital buzzing)
Something that fascinates me is being able
to see where the world is headed.
And right now it's clear
that quantum computers
and AI chatbots are going to
play bigger and bigger roles
in our lives in the coming decades.
Even if we don't know exactly
how they'll be implemented,
I think it's important to
learn how they work right now
and you can do that with this
video's sponsor, Brilliant.
Brilliant has an incredible course
on quantum algorithms.
This one was co-developed
with Microsoft and Alphabet X.
I love that you can simulate
quantum gates and write
and execute real quantum
algorithms right in the lesson.
No need to set up your own
development environment.
And if you want to dive
deeper into cryptography,
making and breaking codes is
really a matter of statistics.
Strong statistical reasoning skills
help us find patterns in data
and make sense of them,
which is crucial to mastering
just about any topic in math
and computer Science.
Brilliant's course on data analysis
will help you ramp up fast.
It uses everyday situations,
like business models to
illustrate key concepts
in statistics and it's interactive,
so you can get hands on
with data visualizations
and develop a real intuition
for interpreting them.
You know the thing that
sets Brilliant apart
is they know how to
break fundamentals down
into their core building blocks,
whether you're learning
math, computer science
or data analysis, Brilliant's
thousands of bite-sized
interactive lessons
help you master key concepts
and build to more advanced topics.
You can try everything
Brilliant has to offer
for free for a full 30 days.
Just go to brilliant.org/veritasium.
I will put that link
down in the description.
And for viewers of this
video, Brilliant is offering
20% off their annual premium subscription
to the first 200 people to sign up.
So I wanna thank Brilliant
for sponsoring this video,
and I want to thank you for watching.